演員：艾爾帕西諾
片名：女人香
克里斯歐唐尼爾
詹姆斯瑞韓
嘉貝拉莉安沃
「1871年屆」
編劇：布格曼
製片兼導演：馬丁布里斯特
「感恩節週末徵人」
「感恩節週末照顧親人」
在我身邊最好別抽
I wish you wouldn't
do that around me.
It's so filthy!
別煩我吧
這是壞習慣
Don't give me a problem
about the cigarettes.
It's such a filthy habit.
老天！看那玩意
Oh, my God!
Look at this.
天啊！
真過份！
Oh, Jesus.
This is so appalling.
難以置信
I can't believe it.
竟然會給他
I can't believe
they gave it to him.
真悲慘
開積架的輸家
Ah, this is pathetic.
Now he's a loser
with a Jaguar.
到底他拍對了誰的馬屁？
Seriously,
who did he have to blow
to get that thing?
早，先生
威利斯早
Good morning, sir.
Mr. Willis.
這跑車真是…
It's really a...
Mr. Trask!
好車
Quite a piece
of machinery.
早，海夫曼
您早，美妙！
Good morning, Havemeyer.
Morning to you, sir.
Bene!
美…妙…
什麼美妙？
Bene?
Bene! Fabulous!
What's fabulous?
您開的那小玩意兒
你覺得我不配？
That fine piece of steel
you have back there.
Ah, you don't think
I deserve it.
不，相反，配得很好
No, sir.
On the contrary.
I think
it's great.
博德的男校長
怎能開破車呢？
Why should the
headmaster of Baird
be seen putt-putting
around in some junker?
我想，董事會諸公
早有此意了吧
In fact, I think the
board of trustees have had
their first true stroke
of inspiration in some time.
謝謝，海夫曼
我照單收下
Well, thank you,
Havemeyer.
I'll take that at face value.
正合我意，先生
I'd expect
nothing less, sir.
祝您今天好
Have a good day.
早安，杭賽克太太
早安
Morning,
Mrs. Hunsaker.
Good morning.
這堆是什麼？
殺人犯名單？
What have we here,
Murderer's Row?
你們講什麼？
What was that about?
沒什麼
和校長打聲招呼而已
Nothing. Just saying hello.
I like to say hello
to Headmaster Trask.
「甘蔗叢」
滑雪場門票
渡假產屋收據
Sugarbush. Lift tickets
and condo vouchers.
不是要去斯朵嗎？
I thought we were
going to Stowe.
「甘蔗叢」就在斯朵
吉米
Sugarbush
is Stowe, Jimmy.
感恩節在佛蒙特
聖誕節到瑞士
This year we're
doing it right.
Thanksgiving in Vermont,
Christmas in Switzerland...
去瑞士吉斯達可貴了！
斯達！
Christmas in Gstaad
is gonna cost us...
"Staad."
G不發音，念斯達
喬治？
The "G" is silent.
"Staad." George?
斯達
斯達什麼？
"Staad."
Trent?
"Staad," man.
So what about Staad?
去那兒少說也要三千元
Fine. The "G" may
be silent,
but it's gonna take at least
three grand to get there.
只好打電話給我爸
I'll have to talk
to my father.
最好快點
要他打給我爸爸
Better yet,
have my father
talk to your father.
我爸再打給你爸
Or my father
talk to your father.
週末回家嗎？
You going home
this weekend, Chas?
不一定
I don't know.
你要回他媽的愛達荷？
You going home
to fuckin' Idaho
for Thanksgiving?
我家在奧勒岡
I'm from Oregon.
他媽的奧勒岡
I meant
fuckin' Oregon.
想不想去滑雪…
Charlie, how do you
feel about skiing?
徜徉在白茫茫的佛蒙特州？
You in the mood for
the white-bosomed
slopes of Vermont?
優惠價，我的朋友打八折
我爸安排的
Got a deal going.
20% off for
my friends.
My father set it up.
聖誕節就去瑞士斯達
Christmas
in Switzerland.
分明念「吉斯達」嘛
是你叫我們念「斯達」的
Staad.
Gstaad.
Dropping the "G" is phony.
You said
everybody
says "Staad."
你又沒去過
復活節去百慕達
然後是肯塔基大賽馬
一道去嘛
Not if you've
been there.
Easter in Bermuda,
then Kentucky Derby
weekend.
We could fit
you in, kid.
去「白茫茫的佛蒙特」
要多少錢？
Well, how much are
these white-bosomed
slopes of Vermont?
一千二
含九道大菜和香檳晚餐
1,200.
Includes a nine-course,
champagne
Thanksgiving dinner.
一千二對我而言是多了
$1,200 is a little rich
for my blood, Harry.
你差多少？
Well, how short
are you?
差到你根本不必問
How short, Harry?
So short it wouldn't be
worth the trouble
of you and George to measure.
還是謝謝你的邀請
But thanks for askin',
all right?
Mmm-hmm.
如果你改變心意的話…
If you change
your mind...
何必問他？他靠獎學金的
What'd you do that for?
You know he's on aid.
假期裡富人總願施捨窮者
On major
holidays, Willis,
it's customary
for the lord of the manor
to offer drippings
to the poor.
你真臭屁！
You're so
full of shit!
羅絲太太！
Hi. Mrs. Rossi?
Yes?
我是來應徵的
I'm here about
the weekend job.
請進
Come on in.
有沒有粉刺？他痛恨粉刺
Does he got pimples?
He hates pimples.
法蘭絲，安靜點
Francine, be quiet.
粉刺，粉刺
Pimples.
Pimples. Yeah.
噓…
Shush!
抱歉，我忘了你名字
I'm sorry. The school
gave me your name,
but I've forgotten it.
查理.西門
It's Charlie Simms.
你好嗎？
好
How are you,
Charlie?
Fine, thanks.
往這兒
Right this way.
這週末都有空嗎？
You're available
the whole weekend?
Yeah.
不回家過感恩節啊？
不
很好！
Not going home
for Thanksgiving?
No.
Good.
本來他在榮民之家
他不喜歡
They put him in
a veteran's home,
but he hated it,
我和爸就接他來了
so I told my dad
that we'd take him.
進去以前先聽我說
Before you go in,
do you mind my
telling you a few things?
不要稱他「長官」
別問太多
Don't "sir" him
and don't ask him
too many questions.
他站不起來時，別去扶他
我一看就知道你能勝任
And if he
staggers a little
when he gets up,
don't pay
any attention.
Charlie,
I can tell you're
the right person for the job.
法蘭克舅舅一定會喜歡你
你們要去哪裡
And Uncle Frank's
gonna like you a lot, too.
Where you gonna be
this weekend?
開車回紐約
We're driving to Albany.
唐尼…
我先生，他家在那兒
Donny, my husband,
has family there.
要不要湯米出去？
Do you want
Tommy in or out?
出去！
Leave him out!
他又在追小野貓了…
從路頭追起呢
He's chasing that
Calico ginch from
the track houses again!
其實他甜的跟糖似的
Down deep, the man
is a lump of sugar.
長官？
Sir?
少叫我「長官」
Don't call me sir.
抱歉，我是說「先生」
長官
I'm sorry.
I mean mister, sir.
啊！來了個白癡
不是嗎？
Uh-oh, we got a moron here,
is that it?
不，先生，那…呃…
中尉，是的，長官，中…
No, mister...
That is...
Lieutenant.
Yes, sir...
中校
Lieutenant Colonel.
服役廿六年
從沒有人連降我四級
Twenty-six years on the line,
nobody ever busted me
four grades before.
進來，笨蛋！
Get in here,
you idiot!
靠近點，我要看清楚
Come a little closer.
I wanna get a
better look at you.
你的皮膚怎樣？
How's your skin, son?
我皮膚，長官？
My skin, sir?
媽呀！上帝！
Oh, for
Christ's sake.
對不起…
叫我法蘭克
I'm sorry, I don...
Just call me Frank.
叫我史雷德先生
或上校，隨你便
就是別叫我長官
Call me Mr. Slade.
Call me Colonel,
if you must. Just don't
call me sir.
好，上校
All right, Colonel.
西門，查理，高三
拿獎學金的，西門？
Simms, Charles.
A senior.
You on
student aid, Simms?
是
Yes, I am.
改叫「獎學金」為「罪犯」
For "student aid"
read "crook."
你父親賣的電話特別昂貴
Your father
peddles car telephones
at a 300% markup.
你母親在照像館上班
Your mother works
on heavy commission
in a camera store.
最會燒特濃咖啡
Graduated to it
from espresso machines.
你呢？患了膽小症
What are you, dying of
some wasting disease?
沒有，我在這兒
No, I'm right...
I'm right here.
我知道你站在哪兒
I know exactly where
your body is.
我要的是個有腦子的看護
What I'm lookin' for
is some
indication of a brain.
踢足球把腦子踢壞了？
詹森總統評福特總統
Too much football
without a helmet?
Hah! Lyndon's line
on Gerry Ford.
我負責簡報
巴黎和談，1968
Deputy Debriefer, Paris,
Peace Talks, '66.
得完「銀星」得「銀熊」
調我去G-2
Snagged the Silver Star
and a silver bar.
Threw me into G-2.
情報大隊嗎？
G-2?
聰明人才能做
你不夠格
Intelligence,
of which you have none.
家在哪？
Where you from?
葛遜，奧勒岡
Gresham, Oregon,
長…上校
Colonel.
爸爸在奧勒岡做什麼的？
What does your daddy do
in Gresham, Oregon?
數碎木片？
Hmm?
Count wood chips?
繼父和媽媽開便利商店
My stepfather and my mom
run a convenience store.
真便利
什麼時候開？
How convenient.
What time they open?
早上五點
5:00 a.m.
打烊呢？
Close?
凌晨一點
1:00 a.m.
很賣力
Hard workers.
真叫我熱淚盈眶
You got me all
misty-eyed!
那你在這鳥不拉屎
的地方幹嘛
So, what are you doing here
in this sparrow-fart town?
我念博德的
I attend Baird.
念博德
Attend Baird!
我知道你上博德
I know you go
to the Baird school.
問題是，你怎麼上的起？
Point is,
how do you afford it,
靠獎學金和老鄉
努力賣玉米？
even with the student aid
and the folks back home
hustlin' corn nuts?
我還得了
「年輕美國之光」獎學金
I won a Young American
merit scholarship.
哇！
Hoo-ah!
榮耀，榮耀屬我主！
Glory, glory
Hallelujah
榮耀，榮耀屬我主！
Glory, glory
Hallelujah
是誰？
Who's there?
那小不點？
That little
piece of tail?
叫她走開！
Get her outta here!
Yeah.
竟然是我們家的種！
Can't believe
they're my blood.
懶鬼的智商
妖精般的禮貌
IQ of sloths and
the manners of banshees.
她爹是技工，她娘是管家
He's a mechanic,
she's a homemaker.
他很懂車…
He knows as much about cars
as a beauty queen,
而她烤的餅乾脆又香
and she bakes cookies,
taste like wing nuts.
生的孩子，卻是白癡
As for the tots,
they're twits.
你的皮膚如何？
我的助理要能站得出去
How's your skin, son?
I like my aides
to be presentable.
嗯，我有幾顆青春痘…
Well, I...
I've had a few zits.
我室友借我保養霜
他是…
But my roommate,
he lent me his Clinique
because he's from
Chestnut Hill
and he's got...
「我的皮膚史」
查理西門著
"The History of My Skin,"
by Charles Simms.
你在唬我？
You patronizing me,
peewee? Hmm?
名校的那套馬屁功？
You givin' me
that old prep school
palaver?
博德學院
Baird School!
流著鼻涕
穿蘇格蘭呢的小鬼
A bunch of runny-nosed
snots in tweed jackets
個個想當喬治布希
all studyin'
to be George Bush.
Well...
布希總統念的是
安多佛學院吧
I believe President Bush
went to Andover, Colonel.
你挑我毛病？
You sharpshootin'
me, punk?
是不是？
Is that what
you're doin'?
少對我「雞蛋裡挑骨頭」
Don't you
sharpshoot me.
先做四十下伏地挺身
再四十
You'll give me 40.
Then you're gonna give me
40 more.
然後就以為能當重任了？
Then you're gonna
pull K.P.,
the grease pit!
我會按著你的頭浸油槽…
I'll rub your nose
in enlisted men's crud
直到你分不清方向
明白嗎？
till you don't
know which end is up!
You understand?
Yeah.
你要什麼？
您什麼意思？
What do you want?
What do you mean,
what do I want?
你所為何來
What do you want here?
我需要一份工作
I want a job.
一份工作
A job!
我好賺錢買機票
回家過聖誕
Yeah, I want a job
so I can make, you know,
my plane fare home
for Christmas.
好，真令人感動
Oh, God,
you're touching!
They used to waltz on the banks
Of the mighty Mississippi
Loving the whole
night through
Till the riverboat gambler
Went off to make a killin'
And bring it on back to you
你還沒走，哭窮鬼？
Still here, poormouth?
Hmm?
便利商店？我的媽！
Convenience store,
my ass!
忙著給老鄉拌調味醬
Hustlin' jalapeno dips
to the appleseeds.
去吧
Go on.
解散
Dismissed.
解散！
Dismissed!
Evangeline
Mrs. Rossi?
查理，我們在這兒呢
上來吧
Charlie, we're up here!
Come on up.
這是唐尼
嗨，查理
This is Donny.
Hey, Charlie.
Hi.
羅絲太太，我搞砸了
不會啦
Mrs. Rossi, I got
the feelin' I screwed up.
Oh, you couldn't have.
面試一團糟
It was a
bad interview.
什麼面試？
只有你來應徵而已
That was no interview,
Charlie. You're it.
You're the only
one that showed up.
You have to take the job.
他睡的多
你可以看電視
打電話給女友
He sleeps a lot. You can
watch television,
call your girlfriend.
輕輕鬆鬆賺三百塊錢
我可不覺得輕鬆
I promise you,
an easy 300 bucks.
I don't get
an easy feeling.
他只是會吼而已
His bark is worse
than his bite.
以前他是大戰英雄
He was a great soldier,
a real hero.
能交心的那種人
The man grows on you.
星期天你們就成哥兒們了
拜託，查理
我和唐尼想去
叔叔卻不想
By Sunday night,
you'll be best friends.
Charlie, please.
I want to get
away with my husband
for a few days,
and Uncle Frank
won't come with us.
六個月前他還看的見光
現在什麼都看不見了
Six months ago,
he could sometimes tell
light from dark,
but now there's nothing.
有人陪他，我比較放心
I just feel better
having someone else
around just in case.
拜託？
Please?
好吧，羅絲太太
謝謝你，查理
Okay, Mrs. Rossi.
Sure.
Thank you, Charlie.
Come here, you.
There you go.
小查！等等！
Chas. Chas, hold up.
你好嗎
好
How you doin'?
I'm good.
那好
That's great.
這本不能借，是參考書
This can't go out.
This is on reserve.
老實說吧
不K這本
老普的課就會當
Here's the thing.
I need the book tonight
for a Thanksgiving quiz
with big-shit Preston
in the morning.
我知道
所以他才不准書外借
Yeah, I know.
That's why he
put it on reserve.
館裡只有一本
This is our only copy.
今晚我要熬夜
沒這本書就死定了
早上七點半一定要還來
Chas, I'm pullin'
an all-nighter.
Without that book
I'm dead, okay?
If it's not back
by 7:30, it's gonna
be my ass.
沒問題
Oh, I promise.
I promise.
Got it?
Yeah.
等等，我得鎖門
Just a second.
I gotta lock up.
Okay.
真等不及放假走人了！
God, can you wait
to get out of this
dump or what?
你要去哪？「甘蔗包」？
Where you guys
going skiing again?
Sugarloaf or...
是「甘蔗叢」，小查
It's bush, Chas,
Sugarbush.
嘿，我哥兒們哪！
你們在幹嘛？
小聲點！明早再報告
That's my boys.
What are you doin'?
Keep your voice down!
I'll tell you about it
in the morning.
What...
杭賽克太太，您好！
Mrs. Hunsaker,
have a nice day?
大呼小叫些什麼
George, why
all the noise?
是杭賽克！快走
It's Hunsaker! Go! Go!
和小查胡鬧罷了！
I was just
messin' around with Chas.
你好，查理
你好
Good evening, Charles.
Hi, Mrs. Hunsaker.
什麼聲音？
不知道啊
What was that?
I don't know, ma'am.
什麼人在那兒啊
天曉得
Who were
those boys?
他們在幹嘛？查理？
Oh, who knows?
What were they doing?
Charles?
Um...
您自己織的圍巾嗎？
不，買的
Did you make this
scarf yourself?
No, George,
I bought it.
是嗎？真是漂亮呆了！
謝了
'Cause it's a beauty.
It really is.
Thank you, George.
感恩節前
恐怕再見不到你了…
In case I don't
see you before
the Thanksgiving holidays,
何不給我抱抱？
抱一個嘛
why don't you give me
one of your big hugs?
Oh, George!
Please?
晚安，男士們
抱一個嘛
Good evening, boys.
Come on.
Goodbye,
Mrs. Hunsaker.
垂斯克先生
是大無畏的領導
Mr. Trask is our
fearless leader,
好學不倦，囫圇吞棗
a man of learning,
a voracious reader.
能用希腦古文背誦
《伊里亞德》
He could recite the lliad
in ancient Greek
還邊在怒溪邊垂釣鱒魚
while fishing for trout
in a rippling creek.
滿腹經書
料事如神
Endowed with wisdom,
of judgment sound,
然而，有一小小疑問
nevertheless about him
the questions abound.
垂斯克先生何德何能？
How does Mr. Trask
make such wonderful deals?
迷得董事會送他積架跑車？
Why did the trustees
buy him Jaguar wheels?
他不奉承
He wasn't conniving.
更不愚昧
He wasn't crass.
只是噘起小嘴
He merely
puckered his lips
舔他們的屁股
and kissed their ass!
來啊
Come on.
再跳
再跳一個
One more.
One more, come on!
你媽的！
Fuck you!
西門先生
威利斯先生
Mr. Simms, Mr. Willis.
Hmm.
杭賽克太太說
昨晚你們都在現場
Mrs. Hunsaker says
that you gentlemen
were at a vantage
point last night
也曾親眼目擊…
該負責的人士
to observe who was
responsible for this
stunt.
是誰？
Who was it?
我真的無可奉告，先生
I really couldn't
tell you, sir.
我確實看到有人在路燈那兒
I thought I saw
someone fooling
with the lamppost,
但再仔細一看，人卻跑了
but by the time
I pulled focus,
they were gone.
西門先生呢？
Mr. Simms?
無可奉告
I couldn't say.
那積架不是我的財產
That automobile
is not just a
possession of mine.
那是董事會交託給我的
That automobile was
presented to me by
the board of trustees.
代表著本校著名的卓越成就
It is a symbol of
the standard of
excellence
for which this
school is known,
我絕不使此精神蒙羞
and I will not
have it tarnished.
那車嗎？
The automobile?
我說的是標準
The standard,
Mr. Willis.
你怎麼說，西門先生？
What's your position,
Mr. Simms?
關於哪方面，先生？
On what, sir?
護衛博德的名譽
On preserving the
reputation of Baird.
我絕對支持
I'm for Baird.
那是誰幹的？
Then, who did it?
我不確定
I really
couldn't say for sure.
很好
Very well.
星期一師生委員會要開會
First thing Monday,
I'm convening
a special session
of the student-faculty
disciplinary committee.
既然此事件關乎全校
全體學生都要出席
As this is a matter
which concerns
the whole school,
the entire student body
will be present.
當天不上課、不舉行活動
There will be
no classes,
no activities.
一切取消
Nothing will
transpire at
this institution
直到判決確認
until that proceeding
is concluded.
如果屆時沒有任何進展
And if, at that time,
we are no further
along than we are now,
兩位就被開除
I will expel you both.
威利斯先生，請先離開
Mr. Willis,
would you excuse us?
感恩節快樂
Have a nice Thanksgiving.
你也一樣，威利斯先生
Thank you.
You, too, Mr. Willis.
我會的
I will.
西門先生
Mr. Simms,
我的話還沒說完
I'm not quite through
with you yet.
本職位的好處之一是
我有權決定一些校務
One of the few perks
of this office is that
I am empowered to handle
certain matters on
my own as I see fit.
明白嗎？
Do you understand?
是的，先生
很好
Yes, sir.
Good.
我和哈佛大學正在談合作
The Dean of
Admissions at Harvard
and I have an arrangement.
除了一般博德申請學生
Along with the usual
sheaf of applicants
submitted by Baird,
of which virtually
會有三分之二被錄取外
我能再加一名
two-thirds are
guaranteed admittance,
I add one name,
一名優秀
但環境不好的學生
somebody who's a standout
and yet underprivileged.
一名付不起
劍橋學雜費的學生
A student who
cannot afford to pay
the board and
tuition in Cambridge.
你知道今年被提名的人
是誰嗎？
Do you know on whose behalf
I drafted a memo this year?
不知道
No, sir.
你
You.
你，西門先生
You, Mr. Simms.
現在你總該告訴我
是誰幹的吧？
Now can you tell me
who did it?
不，先生，我不能
No, sir, I can't.
週末想清楚再說
You take the weekend
to think about it, Mr. Simms.
再會
Good afternoon.
他說什麼？
What'd he say?
沒什麼
什麼意思？
Nothin'.
What do you
mean, nothing?
重講一遍對我們講的話
He said the
same thing.
He just said
it over.
你知道他在幹嘛？
在搞分化啊！
You know what
he's doing?
He's good-cop,
bad-coppin' us.
我是主流，你是非主流
He knows I'm old guard.
You're fringe.
他要打壓我，再哄騙你
He's gonna bear down on me
and soft-soap you.
他有沒有哄你？有沒有？
Did he try to
soft-soap you?
Did he?
沒有
No.
顯然你嚇壞了，有沒有？
Chas, I detect a slight
panic pulse from you.
Are you panicking?
一點點
Yeah, a little.
別慌，你拿獎學金的對吧？
Come on.
You're on
scholarship, right?
Yeah.
你拿獎學金從奧勒岡來博德
You're on scholarship
from Oregon at Baird.
離家可是幾百哩，小查
You're a long way
from home, Chas.
什麼意思？
What's that got
to do with anything?
我不知道你們那兒的習慣…
I don't know how
it works out there.
在這兒，我們很團結
But how it
works here?
We stick together.
我們對他們，絕不變卦
It's us against them,
no matter what.
既不出賣朋友
也不告訴父母
We don't cover our ass.
We don't tell our parents.
個個守口如瓶
Stonewall everybody!
最重要的是…
And above all,
絕對、絕對…
never, ever
不能背棄任何一個哥兒們
leave any of us
twisting in the wind.
就這樣
And that's it.
這些和我拿獎學金
有關係嗎？
What does that have
to do with me being
on scholarship?
Hey, hey.
我只是把情況分析給你聽
I'm just tryin' to
bring you up to speed,
kid, that's it.
謝了
Thanks.
這樣吧
給我幾小時想對策
I'll tell you what.
Give me a few hours
to figure out the moves,
然後打到維州找我
and call me tonight
in Vermont.
我都在「甘蔗叢」別墅
好嗎？
I'll be at
the Sugarbush lodge,
all right?
好吧
All right.
你還好吧？
You all right?
過得去吧
Yeah, I guess so.
Okay.
別讓他每天喝超過四杯
Try to keep him down
to four drinks a day.
別讓他超過四十杯
就不錯啦
If you can keep
him down to 40,
you're doin' good.
你會在酒裡摻水吧？
We try to water
them down a little.
Do you know how to do that?
該走了，親愛的
It's a long ride,
honey.
先搬行李吧，我馬上來
Get the bags in the car.
I'll be right out.
媽咪，別忘了叔公要散步
你每天要帶他出去透透氣
Mommy, Mommy,
don't forget
Uncle Frank's walk.
Oh, yeah.
You have to air him
out a little every day.
你要不要先回他那兒
Why don't you
go on back there,
get yourself oriented?
我馬上過來
給你聯絡電話號碼
I'll come out in a minute,
give you telephone
numbers and stuff.
我絕不會貿然動作的
Well, I wouldn't
try a thing like that
unless I knew, would I?
我來跟她說吧
Just let me
speak to her.
嗨，美人，是你嗎？
昨天我們講過話
Hello, beautiful.
Is that you?
Yeah,
we spoke yesterday.
午飯喝酒了嗎？
聲音好有磁性
You have a glass
of wine with lunch?
You sound
a little dusky. Hmm.
等一下，甜心
Just a minute,
sweetheart.
你回來了？
You're back, huh?
死硬派
取我的藍制服…
櫥子裡的西裝夾裡
Tenacious!
Get out my dress blues.
They're in a garment bag
in the closet.
肩章在梳妝台上…
扣上去
Check the
top dresser drawer.
Take out
the shoulder boards
and affix them,
shoulders
right and left,
盡快，立刻！
ASAP. That means now.
抱歉害你久等
Hello.
Sorry to keep you
waiting, sweetheart.
我不喜歡催人…
I'm not the kind of guy
who likes to rush things,
但是我要坐四點的飛機…
but I'm catchin'
a 4:00 at Logan,
I'm lookin' out my window,
現在連輛禮車也沒看到
and there's
not a taxi in sight.
傑特還捨不得投資
買無線電嗎
那叫司機來聽吧
What happened
to Chet?
He didn't invest
in a radio yet?
Hah! Well,
get your driver on it.
叫他快點
Tell him to get
a move on.
Yes. Mmm.
這等「臥室嗓音」
配的身材一定好
Some kind of body
has got to go with
that bedroom voice.
哪天要去好好瞧瞧
One day I'm gonna swing by,
get a better look at it.
一定
You bet.
Bye.
提袋在床底下，拿出來
My Valpak's
underneath the bed.
Get it out.
制服放進去
Put the boards
on the blues
and fold 'em in.
我們要去哪兒嗎，中校？
Are we going
someplace, Colonel?
關你什麼事？
What business is
that of yours?
別聳肩，小子，我看不見
Don't shrug, imbecile.
I'm blind.
「身體語言」留給小妞兒們吧
Save your body language
for the bimbi.
快去整理我的行李
Now, get my gear out.
Francine, get in the car.
快三點了
原始人還沒出洞呢
It's almost 3:00.
The goddamn Flintstones
haven't left yet.
Willie Rossi
must go in the car.
羅絲太太來了
Here comes
Mrs. Rossi now.
媽的！
Damn it!
今天她已經道別三次了
She said goodbye to me
three times today.
怎麼搞的？
她有分離焦慮症？
What has she got,
separation anxiety?
別讓她進門
Cut her off
at the door.
嗨，親愛的，拜拜，親愛的
Hi, honey.
Bye, honey.
真希望你一起去
I wish you were
coming with us.
我也希望，下次吧
Me, too.
Maybe next time.
小心開車
我們會在這裡
Drive carefully now.
Yeah.
Charlie, this is
where we'll be.
祝好運，別讓他喝太多
Good luck, Charlie.
Don't let him
drink too much.
再見，查理
See you, Charlie.
別讓他打色情專線
他喜歡講髒話
And no 000 numbers.
He loves to talk dirty.
開始工作吧
All right,
let's get to work.
不會扣那個？
L- buckles
givin' you trouble?
沒參加過童子軍
小帥哥？
Never in the
Boy Scouts, sluggo?
我是童子軍新手
I made Tenderfoot.
新手、新腳
Tenderfoot,
my foot!
便利店媽咪的寶寶
我來看看
Convenience store
mama's boy.
Here. Let me
take a look
at that.
敢再碰我我就宰你
小雜種
Touch me again,
I'll kill you,
you little son of a bitch!
只有我能碰你
I touch you.
懂嗎？
Understand?
肩章在最上一格，快去拿
My shoulder boards are
in the top dresser drawer.
Get them, son.
有銀橡樹葉的那對
是這些…？
The epaulets with
the silver oak leaf.
Are these the...
對，車還沒來？
Good.
Taxi come yet?
中校，我們去哪裡？
Colonel,
where are we going?
去哪裡？去看畸形人展
Where are we going?
Freak show central.
在哪裡？
紐約市
Where's that?
New York City.
在紐約州
羅絲太太沒告訴我
That's in New York, son.
New York State.
Mrs. Rossi didn't say
anything to me
about going anywhere.
她忘了
She forgot.
要不要打給她…
你開玩笑啊！
Should we call her,
'cause I...
You kidding me?
他們開著那小破車到阿伯尼時
Call her? By the time
they get to Albany
in that Hupmobile
he drives
大賽馬早開幕了
it'll be opening day
at Saratoga.
我不能去紐約市
Colonel, I can't go
to New York City.
為什麼不能？
Why not?
責任太大
New York...
New York's too
much responsibility.
算了吧，責任！
Ah, responsibility!
我排上有好多小男生
都靠我照顧他們
走吧
I had a lot
of 17-year-olds
in my first platoon.
I took care of them.
All set!
我看起來如何？
How do I look?
機票，錢，演講稿
Tickets. Money.
Speech.
老笑話一則
詹森時代流行的
Old Washington joke
from my days with Lyndon.
我就知道能信得過交通車
你好了？
I knew I could
count on transportation.
Are you ready?
這兒不是板門店
一句「是」就能成事
This is not Panmunjom.
A simple yes will do.
好，拿著，動作要快
Um...
Good! Here you go.
Come on!
Hop to, son!
到我前面，我們走
You're in front of me.
Let's go.
湯姆斯特，快來
Tomster,
come here, boy.
快來
Come on.
湯姆斯特，湯姆斯特…
Here, Tomster, come on.
Tomster, Tomster. Yeah.
記著…
有疑問的時候…
就去做愛
Remember, when in doubt,
fuck.
飛到哪兒，先生？
Good afternoon, sir.
Where's our destination?
紐約市，勇者之家
Our destination
New York City,
home of the brave!
兩位普通艙飛紐約
We got two for
the shuttle
to New York.
我才不「普通」呢
我們是頭等艙
I'm not shuttling anywhere.
Look at those tickets.
First class.
是，頭等艙
Yes, sir,
first class.
你替我買票了？
我沒說過要去紐約啊
Colonel,
you bought me
a ticket?
I never said I'd
go to New York.
你是只敢照規矩做的膽小鬼？
What are you,
some kind of
chicken-shit,
sticks to job
description only?
46號登機門，先生
Gate 46, sir.
謝啦，士官長
As you were, son.
Thank you, sir.
門在哪裡？
Which way's the door?
你瞎了？你瞎了嗎？
當然沒有
Are you blind?
Of course not.
那你媽的猛抓我手幹嘛？
Then why do you keep grabbin'
my goddamn arm?
我才能抓你的手！
I take your arm.
對不起
別對不起了，不知者無罪
你一輩子大概都在看MTV
好啊！
I'm sorry.
Don't be sorry.
How would you know,
watchin' MTV all your life?
Gentlemen?
Yeah!
傑克丹尼爾
好！
Jack Daniels.
You bet.
低卡汽水
And Diet Slice.
The old Diet Slice.
再加一杯水
謝謝你，黛芬妮
不客氣，先生
你怎麼知道她名字？
And a water.
Thank you,
Daphne.
Certainly, sir.
Mmm!
How did you
know her name?
嗯，她擦「芙蕾絲」
Well, she's
wearin' Floris.
英國香水
That's an
English cologne.
但是她又有加州腔
But her voice is
California chickie.
加州小妞嚮往英國淑女
Now, California chickie
bucking for English lady.
所以我叫她黛芬妮
I call her Daphne.
你那小玩意兒
可能會大幹一場
Oh, big things may
happen to that
little thing of yours.
中校…
Look, Colonel,
我陪你去紐約
I'll get you to New York,
all right?
Uh-huh.
然後我就立刻回來
Then I'm gonna have
to turn around and come back.
做你應當做的，查兒
Well, Chuck,
you gotta do
what you gotta do.
叫我查理，或查爾斯
Charlie, all right?
Or Charles.
抱歉，不能怪你
查兒是…
Sorry.
I can't blame you, though.
Chuck is a...
我們為什麼去紐約？
So, why are we
going to New York?
不重要的事你不需要知道
All information will be given
on a need-to-know basis.
Hoo-ah!
黛芬妮呢？找她過來吧
Where's Daphne?
Let's get her down here.
她在後面
She's in the back.
小尾巴在「尾巴」呢
A tail's in the tail.
Hah!
但是我一樣聞得到她
Oh, but I still smell her.
女人…
Women.
能怎麼說呢？
What can you say?
誰創造她們的？
Who made 'em?
上帝真他媽的是天才
God must have been
a fuckin' genius.
秀髮
The hair...
秀髮是最重要的部份
They say the hair
is everything, you know.
有沒有把鼻子
埋在一堆雲鬢中…
Have you ever
buried your nose
in a mountain of curis
然後希望就此睡去的經驗？
and just wanted
to go to sleep forever?
還有香唇
Or lips,
輕輕黏上你的…
and when they touched,
yours were like
就像越過沙漠後
that first swallow of wine
喝下的第一口美酒
after you just crossed
the desert.
乳房
Tits!
Hoo-ah.
大的，小的…
Big ones, little ones,
乳頭瞪著你
像秘密探照燈
nipples staring
right out at you
like secret searchlights.
Mmm.
還有腿…
And legs...
不管是不是符合黃金比例
I don't care if
they're Greek columns
或像二手貨的史坦威鋼琴
or secondhand Steinways.
兩腿中間的…
What's between 'em,
正是通往天堂的護照
passport to heaven.
我得喝一杯
I need a drink.
是的，西門先生
Yes, Mr. Simms,
這世上只有兩個字動聽…
there's only two syllables
in this whole wide
world worth hearing.
陰部
Pussy.
Hah!
你有沒有在聽？
這可是智慧結晶
Are you listening to me, son?
I'm givin' you pearis here.
你真的很喜歡女人
勝於一切
I guess you
really like women.
Oh, above all things!
遠次於女人，排名第二的
A very, very
distant second
是法拉利跑車
is a Ferrari.
查理
Charlie?
給我你的手
Give me your hand.
此乃你教育的開始
「華爾道夫大飯店」
This is just the start
of your education, son.
Hoo-ah.
我們在哪裡？
Where are we?
Where are we, eh?
一切文明的中心
The cynosure of
all things civilized.
華爾道夫大飯店
The Waldorf-Astoria.
上次是和布魯塞爾同事
一起來的
The last time I
was here, Charlie,
was with a G-2 from Brussels.
他有部法拉利
Had a Ferrari.
每天我都幫他開車門
他竟然沒邀我兜過風
Every day I
held the door open
for the fucker.
Never even
offered me a ride.
去他的
Well, fuck him.
他死了，我瞎了
He's dead and I'm blind.
幫我找個妞兒
Spread the word.
Thank you, sir.
And the intelligence
will be forthcoming?
什麼？
Sir?
找個妞兒
是的，歡迎光臨華爾道夫
On the
escort scene.
Yes, sir.
And welcome to
the Waldorf.
多謝，朋友
Gracias, amigo.
波多黎各人
是最好的陸戰隊
Puerto Ricans.
Always made
the best infantrymen.
Oh!
又回家啦！
I'm home again.
給我來點酒
Give me an inventory
on this, will you?
我在哪？亞洲嗎？
All right, where am I,
in Asia?
他說電話在房間另一頭
He told me the phone
was on the other side
of the room, didn't he?
在那兒呢？
By the windows?
在這裡
It's right here.
Okay.
咱們上路啦
We're in business.
請接橡樹廳
Get me the Oak Room.
酒夠嗎？
只有吉米賓和早時年兩種
How's that inventory
comin'?
There's Jim Beam
and Early Times.
補給官又給收買了！
Quartermaster's
on the take again.
薛登或麥克在嗎？
Hello. Is Sheldon
or Mack there?
我是法蘭克史雷德中校
This is Lieutenant
Colonel Frank Slade.
以前是常客
和巴將軍來過
I used to be a regular.
I used to come in
with a General Garbisch.
大概是因為他現在住地府吧
Yes, that's
probably because he's at
Arlington, six feet under.
我要一張桌子，兩個人
別靠廚房，八點十五
Listen up.
I want a table for two,
and I don't mean Siberia,
15.
把瓶子清掉
Clear them little
bottles off.
我打完電話
你就叫海曼來
And when I get
off the phone,
call up Hyman.
我要滿滿一房間的
「約翰丹尼爾」
你是說「傑克丹尼爾」？
Tell him I want it
wall to wall
with John Daniels.
Don't you mean
Jack Daniels?
熟客才這麼叫的
He may be Jack to you, son.
But when you've known him
as long as I have...
是玩笑
這是史中校
八點我要轎車
That's a joke. Hello!
This is Lieutenant
Colonel Frank Slade.
I would like a limo,
00.
你要喝什麼？
What are you drinkin'?
不用，謝謝，我不喝酒
Nothing, thanks.
I don't use it.
那有什麼「用」？
What's useful about it?
中校，我要走了
I don't know.
Listen, Colonel,
I have to get going.
走去哪？
Where you goin'?
回學校
有很重要的事要做
Back to school.
I've got some real
important stuff I
have to take care of.
好啊
Very well.
但我從不讓助理餓著走
But I never let
my aides leave
on an empty stomach.
吃完晚餐
我司機會送你
You'll dine with me
and then my driver
will transport you
往波士頓的飛機十點起飛
to the airport for
the Boston shuttle
departing at 2200 hours.
現在，打開我的行李箱
Meanwhile,
unpack my bag.
我要上廁所
I'm gonna christen
the latrine.
你叫什麼，司機？
What's your name,
driver?
曼尼，先生
Manny, sir.
華爾道夫的小廝…
這裡的小妞好不好？
Manny. The bellhops
at the Waldorf,
are they any good
at getting escorts?
我不知道，先生
I wouldn't know, sir.
那你知道什麼？
What would you know?
哪方面的？
About what?
你知道哪方面？
About you-know-what?
你知道我能做點安排
Maybe I could
manage something.
我要的可是一流的
I'm talkin'
top of the line, now.
我想一想，先生
Let me think
about this, sir.
你怎麼回事？
What's the matter
with you?
我？
With me?
車感覺沉重，怎麼搞的？
全世界都在你肩上了
Yeah. Car feels heavy.
You know why?
You got the fuckin'
weight of the world
on your shoulders.
學校裡出了點事
I got a little problem
at school, that's all.
講吧
Spit it out!
不是大事
我們去橡樹廳？
It's not a big deal,
all right?
Where we going,
the Oak Room
or somethin'?
你說是「重要的事」
你和院長女兒上床了？
If it's not a big deal,
why did you say
real important stuff?
What are you doin',
banging the dean's daughter?
Hah!
不是，惹了點麻煩而已
I'm just in
a little trouble.
哪一類的？
What kind of trouble?
我看到有些傢伙做的些事
I saw some guys
doing something.
要不要說，不然有得賠
To tell or not to tell,
or it's your ass.
Hmm?
你怎麼知道？
我是男巫
細說從頭
How'd you know that?
I'm a wizard.
Give me the details,
come on.
有個叫哈瑞的，很有錢
他當頭兒
There's this guy
at school named Harry.
He's this
real rich kid,
and he like,
runs the show.
別人呢？
Who else?
另一個叫喬治
什麼也沒做
There's another guy, George,
but George didn't do anything.
我們看到哈瑞那伙做的事
George and I saw
Harry and his buddies
doin' somethin'.
現在博德的人…
Now, the folks at Baird,
知道你和喬治能抓出元兇
they know you and George
can identify
the guilty parties?
他們以為我們會
喬治是你的朋友
Yeah, they think we can.
George is
a friend of yours.
不是，不過他人不壞
He's not a friend,
but he's all right.
你相信他？
You trust him?
大概吧
Yeah, I guess so.
他也拿獎學金？
He's on
scholarship, too?
沒有，有關係嗎？
No, why?
我們有喬治、哈瑞和麻煩
We got George,
we got Harry,
we got trouble.
他們有錢，你沒錢
你想有錢
They're rich, you're poor.
You wanna get rich.
你想畢業後像他們一樣有錢
You wanna graduate Baird,
become a rich
big shot like them.
對不對？
不，不完全是
Am I right?
No.
It's not that
way at all.
好吧，查理
Okay, Charlie!
到了，橡樹廳
Here we are, gentlemen,
the Oak Room.
橡樹廳！
The Oak Room!
菜單和雙份傑克丹尼爾加冰
Bring us a menu and
double Jack Daniels
on the rocks.
Charlie, sit down here.
也許您穿上這件會更舒服些
你很帥
Perhaps you'll feel more
comfortable in this, sir.
You look great!
Thank you.
這就是橡樹廳
Here we are, Charlie,
the Oak Room.
現在念菜單吧
Now, read me
the bill of fare.
好
Let's see.
橡樹廳漢堡加薯條
要24塊錢
You got the Oak Room
burger and fries for $24.
酒呢？上菜慢的像泥巴
Where's the booze?
Flowin' like
mud around here.
24塊的漢堡？
A $24 hamburger?
怎麼搞的？
What's the story?
什麼？
What story?
你不是個
有錢的守財奴？
Are you a rich
miser or something?
Hah!
不是，只是個普通瞎子罷了
No, I'm just
your average blind man.
「普通瞎子」
Your average
blind man.
你怎麼付這些錢呢？
How do you plan on paying
for all this stuff?
用乾乾淨淨的美鈔
Crisp, clean dollars.
American.
我存的傷殘退休俸
I saved up my
disability checks.
你存了多少？
我們坐頭等艙還住華爾道夫
吃24塊錢的漢堡
How much did you save?
I mean, we flew first class,
we're at the Waldorf-Astoria,
a $24 hamburger restaurant.
計劃的一部份
All part of
a plan, Charlie.
要不要告訴我？
You want to let
me in on it?
為什麼要？你又不關心
Why should I?
You're not interested.
You don't give a shit!
你就要坐末班飛機走了
You're leavin' on that
last shuttle
out of LaGuardia.
Hmm? Ooh!
只剩15分鐘
可能趕不上
You got 15 minutes, son.
I don't think
you're gonna make it.
除非橡樹廳陽台上
有直升機
Unless the Oak Room
keeps some
complimentary
helicopter on the roof.
不，不，先生
No, sir. No!
你得待到明天
You're here till tomorrow.
你說最後班機十點起飛
You said the last shuttle
leaves at 2200 hours.
That's 10:00, right?
我是這麼聽說的
Last I heard, yeah.
現在只有八點半
It's only ·:30.
騙你的，飛機九點起飛
I lied. Leaves at 0:00.
九點起飛？
It leaves at 0:00?
別緊張
事實是，查理…
Calm down. Calm down.
Ahh! The truth is,
Charlie,
我需要一隻導盲犬
幫我執行計劃
I need a guide dog
to help me execute my plan.
什麼計劃？
What plan?
你有權利知道
You have a right to know.
不全是計劃
比較像旅行
It's not really a plan,
Charlie. It's sort of a...
More like a tour,
小小的快樂之旅
a little tour
of pleasures.
一流的飯店，美食…
Stay in a first-class hotel,
eat an agreeable meal,
飲一杯好酒
drink a nice
glass of wine,
看我大哥…親情最偉大
see my big brother.
Nothing like family,
you know.
然後和一個妙女郎做愛
And then, make love
to a terrific woman.
再然後
After that...
Yeah?
我要躺在華爾道夫的
豪華大床
I'm gonna lie down on
my big, beautiful bed
at the Waldorf
把我的腦袋射爛
and blow my brains out.
能向您建議特餐嗎？
May I tell you
our specials?
可以
You may, sir.
今日特餐有嫩烤碧玉絲…
和胡椒子
Tonight we have
charred venison with
buckwheat spaetzle
and green peppercorn.
焗茄子
Grilled veal paillards,
tomato tapenade,
and roasted eggplants.
我在流口水呢
Get me a napkin.
My mouth's watering.
如果您要奶酥派
現在就要點
If you would like our
cr·me souffl· for dessert,
it would be a good
idea to order now.
先點奶酥，其他的想一想
Yes, on the souffl·.
Give us a half a minute
on the rest.
很好，先生
Very good, sir.
我想吃烤碧綠絲
I'm leaning
towards the spaetzle.
史中校…
桌上有小麵包嗎？
Colonel Slade...
Charlie, rolls on the table?
給我，你一定要嘗嘗
Give 'em to me.
You should
try these rolls, Charlie.
我在華楚卡堡時做夢都夢到
科羅拉多以西的麵包就不行了
I used to dream about them
when I was at Fort Huachuca.
Colonel Slade...
Bread's no good
west of the Colorado.
水太鹹
Water's too alkaline.
史中校，剛才您說…
Colonel Slade,
did you say...
我沒聽錯吧？
Did I hear you right?
你說你要自殺？
You said you're gonna
kill yourself?
不對
我說我要把腦袋打爛
No.
I said I was gonna
blow my brains out.
試試小麵包
我幫你塗奶油
Try one of these
rolls, Charlie.
I buttered it for you.
我不要吃
I don't want a roll,
all right?
那就吃點紅蘿蔔
Okay. Have a radish!
Hah!
哈囉
再來一杯雙份的傑克丹尼爾
Hello! Bring me
a double Jack Daniels
on the rocks.
立刻就來，先生
Yes, sir.
Right away.
拜託，別來那套
Please, don't do that.
不要
Don't do that.
Hmm.
真是好地方！
What a marvelous place.
Okay.
Yeah.
你睡這兒
Your billet is here.
床具在櫃裡
You'll find bedding
in the closet on the shelf.
早晨要還原成起居間
In the morning,
the area will be
returned to
sitting-room mode
不能睡過七點
no later than
0700 hours.
你做什麼？
What was that?
沒什麼
Nothing.
下次，快動作
Next time
snap it out!
大姆指頂掌心
食指要對準
成一齊線，頂住眉線
放下！
Thumb to palm, index finger
through little digit,
smartly aligned,
sharp to the hairline,
down!
比你優秀的好多人
都敬過禮
Too many men,
far better than you,
have executed
that courtesy.
你要是聰明的話
就別再做
And if you're smart,
you won't try it again.
這老蝙蝠的雷達
可不是蓋的
This bat has
got sharper radar
than the Nautilus.
少跟我玩花招，查理
Don't fuck with me,
Charlie.
好好睡一覺，孩子
See you get
a good night's
sleep, son.
「今天多美好」
It's a lovely day today
「不論做什麼」
So, whatever you gotta do
「都是好日子，沒錯！」
You got a lovely day
to do it in, that's true
早安，查理
Good morning, Charlie.
Good morning.
這是蘇菲亞
This is Sofia, Charlie.
帶針線的魔術師
她在替我做衣服
She's a magician
with a needle.
Sofia's workin' me up
a little Glen Plaid number,
我請她也替你做一件
and I've asked her if
she'd put something
together for you.
我不需要衣服，中校
I don't need
any clothes, Colonel.
上流大都會任務的必備品
Standard issue
for an upscale
urban assignment.
如果你不喜歡
任務完了就丟
You don't like the clothes,
Charlie,
on completion of duty,
you can give 'em away.
推車上有咖啡和小餅乾
Juice, coffee,
and other assorted goodies
on the trolley over there.
快起來打點一下
Get yourself up,
get yourself together.
「這是唱歌的好日子」
It's a great day
for singin' a song
「也是前進的好日子」
And it's a great day
for movin' along
「從早到晚都是好時光」
And it's a great day
from morning to night
「這是好日子」
And it's a great day
「適合許心願」
For everybody's plight
今天覺得怎樣？
How are you feeling
today, Colonel?
棒，棒極了
Super!
Superior!
沒必要的
Superfluous!
蘇菲感恩節上班
她半工半讀
Young Sofie here
is working Thanksgiving
because she's trying to
put herself through college.
我告訴她你也在上學
I told her, "My young friend
Charlie's headed for college."
抱歉
Excuse me.
你去哪？
Where you goin'?
打電話
I need to use
the phone.
這兒有電話
What's wrong with
the phones in here?
我怕打擾你
I don't want
to disturb you.
你不會，在這兒打
You're not disturbing me.
Make your call.
我需要隱私
I'd kind of like
to be private.
不准進我房間
Stay out of my room!
這兒夠隱私啦
This is as private
as you're gonna get.
But if
you've got somethin'
that must be done
And it can only
be done by one
可不可能讓你也換上西裝？
Sofia,
what are the chances
of suitin' you
up sometime?
「甘蔗叢賓館」
請接喬治威利斯
Sugarbush Lodge.
George Willis, please.
Hello.
喬治，我是查理
明年你一定要和我們一起來
George! Hey, it's Charlie.
Hey, Chas.
Next year you gotta
come up with us.
白粉灑在兔女郎身上
White powder on
a base of snow bunnies.
你聽到了嗎？
Chas, are you there?
你叫我打給你，問你計劃
Yeah, I'm here.
You told me to call
you for the moves.
All right.
目前，計劃是按兵不動
保持現狀，先擱在一旁
For now, the move's
no move, status quo.
Everything's
the way we left it.
怎麼擱？
How did we leave it?
沒聽到也沒看到
See no evil,
hear no eviI.
懂我意思吧？
You know
what I mean, Chas?
沒聽到也沒看到
Yeah. See no evil,
hear no evil.
好，輕輕鬆鬆
Okay, then,
walk like you talk.
All right, bye.
喬治威利斯？
George Willis, huh?
Yeah.
喬治威利斯
他爹可能是一世
George Willis.
That makes his
father probably
George Willis, Senior.
查理，我問你…
Charlie, I ask you,
你猜老喬治會怎麼反應？
小喬治所說的
「沒看沒聽到」
what do you think
big George is gonna feel
about little George
seeing no evil,
hearing no evil?
我們說好不告訴爸媽的
是我們的秘密
Well, we're not gonna
tell our parents.
We're just gonna keep it
between ourselves.
喬治不告訴他爸？
真夠義氣
我喜歡你把我弄痛
告訴我，查理…
Oh, George isn't gonna tell
his father about this thing!
Damn decent of him.
Scusi, Colonnello.
Prego.
I love it
when you hurt me.
Tell me now,
Charlie.
喬治威利斯的老爸
是幹嘛的？
This George Willis, Jr.,
what's his father do?
不曉得
I don't really know.
我來告訴你
Well, I'm gonna tell you.
當他不忙著當保險公司大經理
When George Willis, Senior,
isn't busy as
a million-dollar man
for Aetna Casualty...
或通用汽車駐英國總監的時候
Or is it
New England distributor
for the Chrysler
Corporation?
他會關心兒子的生活起居
He concerns himself
with his young son,
George Willis, Jr.
喬治不會告訴他爸爸
George isn't going
to say anything
to his father.
Oh, Charlie.
老喬治會扭緊小喬治的發條
Big George is gonna
wind up little George,
後者就會知無不言
and little George
is gonna sing
like a canary.
你要聰明的話
你就先發制人
And if you're hip, kid,
you're gonna hop to, too.
你都看透了嘛
You've got this
all figured out,
don't you?
不需要拿獎學金就能看透
It don't take no
Young American merit
scholarship to
figure this one out.
你有你的人生，你念博德
Charlie,
you had a little life,
so you decided
to go to the
Baird school
因為你想有前途
to put yourself
in the market
for a big one.
要想不被淘汰
你就得說出來
Now, in order to stay
in the running,
you're gonna have
to tell these people
what they want to know.
真的嗎？
好了嗎，蘇菲亞？
You think so?
Are we finished, Sofia?
Yes.
Grazie. Grazie.
Andate.
你要是現在不說
Charlie,
if you don't sing now,
就會落得…
在奧勒岡看一輩子的便利店
you're gonna end up,
not only shelving biscuits
in some convenience store
in the Oregon 'burbs,
而且在你翹辮子前聽到的話…
是你對客人說的「多謝光臨」
but probably the last
word you'll ever hear
yourself say
just before you croak,
gonna be,
"Have a nice day
and come back soon."
快量查理的尺寸
我們要赴約
Sofia!
Measure up
Charlie, here, pronto.
We got a date
for Thanksgiving.
我們要去赴約？
We got a date?
我大哥家，白原鎮
紐約州
My brother's place.
W.R. Slade,
White Plains, New York.
我不能跟你去你大哥家
Colonel, I can't go with you
to your brother's place.
我要趕回學校去
I mean, I should be
getting back to school.
你總得過感恩節吧？
Well, you gotta have
Thanksgiving somewhere.
吃點，玩點
I mean, eats and treats.
我又正好缺個伴
I can use
the company, Charlie.
All right.
他知道我要來嗎？
Does he know
I'm comin'?
他不知道我要來
我進門時你注意看他臉
He doesn't know
I'm comin'.
But wait till you see
the look on his face
when I walk
through the door.
他愛我
Oh, he loves me!
噢，查理…
至於你的麻煩
Oh, Charlie,
about your
little problem,
世上有兩種人
勇於負責的人
there are two kinds
of people in this world:
Those who stand up
and face the music,
和去找靠山的人
有靠山比較好
and those who
run for cover.
Cover's better.
好啦，蘇菲亞，給他穿上
Okay, Sofia, suit him up!
讓他帥點！
Make him pretty.
小心
Careful.
要按門鈴嗎？
好
Should I ring it?
Yeah.
什麼事？
什麼事？你是誰？
Yes?
Yes!
Who is this?
藍迪
It's Randy.
藍迪？你是我新親戚？
Randy? You new?
我是你外甥
我來啦
你姐姐可是想死我了
I'm your nephew.
Hah! Here I am!
Your sister's been
hoarding me
long enough.
散財的時候到啦！
Thought it's time
to spread the
riches around.
法蘭克叔叔
葛蘿莉亞
Uncle Frank.
Gloria!
吉兒
來嘛，說聲哈囉…
我可是大老遠從紐約來的
Gail.
Of course.
Say hello to the potluck
party from New York City.
你的法蘭克叔叔和查理西門
Good old Uncle
Frank and this here
with him is Charlie Simms,
博德學院足球隊中衛
star halfback of the
Baird football team.
他們打敗艾斯特隊和國頓
連阿納斯中學都不是對手
They not only beat
Exeter and Groton,
but Aquinas High School, too.
你們倒霉的爹在哪？
Where's your
miserable father?
不，等等，嚇他一跳
叫他的肥心臟跳一下！
威利！
Wait! No, no.
Let's surprise him.
Give that fat
heart of his
an attack. Willie!
威利！
Ho, Willie!
哈囉！法蘭克
Hello, Frank.
你好？這是我助理
How you doin'?
Okay.
Here's my hand.
查理，見過史雷德先生
Charlie, meet
W.R. Slade.
Nice to meet you, sir.
最典型的公事箱男士！
The original
bulging briefcase man.
葛心，有梅子的味道！
是不是有烤火雞？
是的，法蘭克
Gretchen, I smell
those prunes!
We talkin'
turkey Marbella?
Yes, we are.
咱們來聞聞，來嘛
我一向暗戀著你
Let's have a whiff.
Come on.
You know, I always
had a sneaker for you.
Come here.
你跑那去了，蓋瑞？
Where are you, Garry?
I heard you cough.
Right here.
你說你是誰來著？
Who are you again?
我待在華爾道夫和…
您是他大哥嗎？
I'm here at
the Waldorf with...
Is it your brother?
大哥的小寶貝，你好
W.R.'s final issue.
How ya doin', son?
他是我弟弟，你又是誰？
Yeah, sure,
Frank's my brother.
Who the hell are you?
我算他的看護吧
I'm takin' care of him
for the weekend.
Charlie.
抱歉，酒呢？
這兒的步調真慢
Sorry.
Where's the booze?
Flowin' like mud here.
老實說吧
中校情況不太好
To tell the truth,
the Colonel's not well,
I don't think.
不太好？
Not well?
我想他很寂寞
I think he's
a little lonely.
那你帶他回你家去
Why didn't you
take him to your
family's for dinner?
我聽到了
I heard that!
別管我，查理
「老大哥經」
I heard that.
Pay no attention
to him, Charlie.
That's just big-brother talk.
從我出生起他就管著我
He's been watching out
for me since day one.
替我收的爛攤子
連他也記不清
Bailed me out of more trouble
than he'd like to remember.
我來幫你放大衣
Here, let me
take your coat.
本來要帶酒來的
竟然忘了
I meant to pick up
some vino on my way up,
but I blew it.
聖誕節給你們寄好酒
先看看今天處得好不好吧
I'll send you the
Rothschild again
for Christmas,
only let's see how
Thanksgiving goes.
我再加兩個位子
你的酒
I'll set two
more places.
Here's
your drink, Frank.
謝謝
還在雪後糖廠工作？
Thank you, Randy.
Still with
Snow Queen Sugar?
是雪焰
你怎麼老是搞錯？
Snow Flake.
Why do you always
get that wrong?
反正對錯也不重要
你做什麼
Because it's not
important for me
to get it right.
What are you doing
there now?
市場行銷副總裁
恭喜，雖然糖很糟糕
I'm vice president
for marketing.
Hoo-ah!
Congratulations!
Sugar is shit, though.
我告訴阿伯姆將軍…
改供蜂蜜，糖會要人命
I told General Abrams,
install honey in
the commissaries.
If K-50s didn't
blow your brains out,
sugar, sure as shit,
was gonna.
我們何不都坐下？
Why don't we
all sit down?
Ooh.
誘人的「蜜祖琪」
小心
老婆靜不下來的時候
她就如狼似虎了
Mitsouki. Rhymes
with nookie.
Be careful.
When the wife
gets restless,
the wife gets racy.
吃飯吧
Well, let's
go and eat,
shall we?
跟我來
By all means.
Thank you, Charlie.
你想坐哪，法蘭克？
還是主位？
Where you
wanna sit, Frank?
At the head again?
麻將桌也成
這兒很好
Any old card table
will do. This is fine.
我講到哪了？
Where was I?
我早上四點醒來
不知道身邊是誰
So, I wake up.
It's 4:00 in the morning.
I don't know who I'm with
也不知道人在哪
or why I'm there,
or where I am.
這朵亞洲小野花…
What am I gonna do?
I got this Asian flower
躺在一邊
巧笑倩兮
on one hand,
all giggly and dewy-like,
力大如牛的海軍護士
躺在另一邊
and this hard-boiled
Navy nurse outta Omaha,
on the other.
三個成人一張床
一件衣裳也沒穿
We're three across
the bed, not a stitch
of clothes on.
我忽然有了點子！
It comes to me.
東西匯合，性橋一座！
Let east meet west.
We'll build a
golden bridge.
簡直像個工程大隊！
I felt like I'd just joined
the corps of engineers!
你們還在聽？
We all still here?
好美的故事
It's a
beautiful story.
你語不驚人死不休是吧？
Do you always enjoy
shocking people,
Uncle Frank?
Honey...
沒想到你這麼容易被驚
I didn't know
you were so
easily shocked, Randy.
佩服你的敏感
I admire your
sensibilities,
I'm touched.
爸，記得你叫法蘭克
去狗屋的事？
Dad, remember the time
you persuaded Frank
to go to the kennel?
怎麼樣？
What about it?
他差點把人家生意毀了
He almost put
the seeing eye dog business
outta business.
夠了
Cool it, Randy.
都過去了
It's over and done with.
可不是嘛，蓋瑞
Indeed it is, Garry.
都過去了，晚餐也完了
Indeed it is.
So is dinner.
查理，幾點了？
我們該走了
Charlie, what time
you have?
I think we better
be gettin' back.
有沒有想過換隻盲人錶？
You ever given
any thought to
a Braille watch, Frank?
Randy...
史提夫汪達也戴
你不喜歡是吧？
Stevie Wonder wears one,
or do you rank on him, too?
甜心，夠了
Honey, please.
沒關係，葛蘿莉亞…
It's all right, Gloria.
I enjoy Randy's
observations.
我太太叫葛兒，法蘭克！
你聽到沒？是葛兒
My wife's name
is Gail, Frank.
Can you hear that?
Gail.
對不起，葛兒
Excuse me.
Gail.
葛兒一定是個漂亮女人
Gail strikes me as
a very beautiful woman,
但是她的聲音裡透著緊張
but, you know,
there's a little
tension in her voice.
可能有一兩個原因
I don't know what it is.
It could be one
of two things,
她緊張，或者不滿現狀
either Gail is nervous
or unsatisfied.
你什麼意思？
What's your point,
Uncle Frank?
你應該親她那裡
You ought to
go down on her.
住口，法蘭克
Cut it out, Frank,
will ya?
你滿腦子放在糖生意上
卻忘了真正的蜜糖！
You've gotten
so wrapped up
in sugar,
you forgotten
the taste of
real honey!
法蘭克，住口
Frank, for
God's sake!
聽到沒？
她衣裳下有熊熊烈火
Hear that voice?
There's fire
under that dress.
住口！
你給我出去！
Will you cut it out?
Just get the fuck
outta here.
到花街去吧！
跟你同類在一起
Hoo-ah!
Get in your limousine.
Go down to the Bowery.
Get with the other fucking
drunks, where you belong!
等一等…
Wait a minute.
幹嘛
別認真
What?
Can you take it easy?
為什麼？你要我讓他
因為他是瞎子，「查仔」？
What for?
You want me to lay off him,
Chucky, 'cause he's blind?
不是，但…
No, but...
我朋友的名字是查理
My friend's name is Charles.
別叫他查仔
He doesn't like to
be called Chucky.
今天是一家人團圓
This is supposed to be
a family get-together.
我先警告你了
Just a warning.
老天爺！
又來一個把白癡當英雄的笨蛋
還是過氣的！
Jesus Christ,
another sucker who thinks
this shit-heel's a war hero.
Hoo-ah!
Well, once, maybe.
他一定跟你吹過他
當詹森幕僚
I suppose he told
you about his days on
Lyndon Johnson's staff?
本來我要走，現在不了
I was gonna go.
Now I'm not leaving.
法蘭克本來被內定升將軍
Frank was earmarked
for general.
內定…好字眼
Earmarked, good word.
但是他朝每個人亂開炮
Frank likes to spit
in everybody's eye!
夠了
Randy, that's enough.
他們…
軍中術語是什麼來著
So they, what do they call it,
when they give you the
shaft in the military?
跳過！
Passed over!
法蘭克就被跳過了
Right, Frank was
passed over
for promotion.
好幾次
Couple times.
結果…
You wanna know
what happened then?
閉嘴！
Will you shut
your mouth?
他自己搞砸了
He blew himself up.
住口！
Stop it, Randy.
中校拿著手榴彈…
在布拉格堡還是什麼的鬼地方
Our Colonel here had
a grenade juggling act
at Fort Bragg, or wherever
it was they dumped him.
班寧堡
Fort Benning.
他正在教白刃戰…
He was teaching
hand-to-hand combat
to second lieutenants...
跟我講話時候要看著我
Randy, look at me when
you're talking to me,
now, son.
我是在看，法蘭克
他的夥伴是上尉…
I'm lookin', Frank.
His partner in the act
was some captain.
文生史奎斯少校
管他是誰
Major Vincent Squires.
Whoever he was.
他們先喝早餐酒
法蘭克喝的是伏特加
夥伴喝的是血腥瑪莉
Before going on, they'd
have a lo-cal breakfast,
a screwdriver for Frank,
bloody mary for his partner.
文生又愛喝混酒
No, Vincent drank
Sea Breezes.
班寧堡的法官說法蘭克喝的
至少是他夥伴的四倍
The Judge Advocate
at Benning said
Colonel Slade had four
to his partner's one.
他在課堂上騰雲駕霧
他開始拉出插銷
He's really
flying in class.
He gets all excited.
He starts pulling
the pins out.
一枚手榴彈鬆了手
One grenade got
away from him.
碰…！
Boom.
鬆手的那枚…
The one that got away.
法蘭克堅持沒拔插銷
The pin was in,
Frank claims.
有什麼差別？
In or out, what
difference does it make?
哪個笨蛋會去玩手榴彈？
What kind of
fucking lunatic
juggles grenades?
文生倒沒事
Vinnie came out okay.
法蘭克也只不過瞎了而已
想不想聽實話？
你猜是什麼？
All Frank lost
was his eyesight.
You wanna know
the truth?
Got a handle
on that, do you?
他以前是個王八蛋
He was
an asshole before.
Hoo-ah!
現在是個瞎了眼的王八蛋
上帝很好玩
Now all he is,
is a blind asshole.
Hoo-ah.
Hey, God's a funny guy.
挺有幽默感的
God doth have
a sense of humor.
也許上帝覺得
有人不配去看
Maybe God thinks
some people don't
deserve to see.
Hoo-ah.
懂了吧？「查仔」
You get
the point, Chucky?
他叫查理
His name is Charles.
會不會念？查理
You can say that,
can't you? Charles.
知道這是什麼吧？
以前我教那些小鬼的鎖喉扣
Know what this is, Randy?
It's a Ranger choke hold.
From teaching
those lieutenants.
Colonel, let go.
再使點力
你的氣管就破了
Little pressure,
I bust your windpipe.
我不介意的
I don't care
what he said to me.
After me.
查理
中校，我們走吧
Charles.
Just let go, please!
葛心…
Gretchen?
你菜燒得比上次好
You outdid yourself.
你可把我迷住了
明年我們吃火雞大餐
If you twist my
arm hard enough,
we're talking
turkey Marbella
next year.
也許吧？
Who knows?
Frank?
再會，威利
Goodbye, Willie.
我是爛人
I'm no fucking good.
一直都是
And I never have been.
走吧，查理，拿大衣
小心
Come on, Charlie,
get the coats.
Colonel.
Watch your step.
Hold it.
回紐約，兄弟！
走吧
Nueva York,
compadre. Vamos!
有沒戴錶？
You got a watch?
七點廿分
It's 7:20.
我問你有沒有戴錶
不是幾點
I didn't ask you the time.
I asked if you had a watch.
在另一個房間
Yeah, in the other room.
去拿
Get it.
你床旁邊有鐘
Colonel, there's a clock
right next to your bed.
有沒有秒針？
Does it have
a second hand?
有
替我計時
Yeah.
Time me!
多久？
How long?
差不多三十秒
About 30 seconds.
我老了
I'm rusty.
你哪來的槍？
Where did you get
a gun, Colonel?
「零件」或「武器」
別叫它做槍
Piece or weapon,
Charlie,
never gun.
你從哪來的這些零件？
Where did you
get the piece?
我是美國陸軍軍官
它是我的隨身配備
I'm an officer
in the US Army.
This is my sidearm.
可是你已經退役了
我是退役了，又怎樣
But you're not
an officer anymore.
So I'm retired,
so what?
軍官永遠不離他的點45
An officer never
relinquishes his.45.
最好把它給我
不然我打電話給羅絲太太
You better relinquish
it to me or I'm gonna
have to call Mrs. Rossi.
好主意
Good idea.
不然我就回學校
Then I'm going
back to school.
更好！窗外有藍天
旅途愉快
Even better.
Blue skies, green lights.
I hope you have
a wonderful trip.
應該只花了廿五秒吧？
你量了沒有？
That felt like 25.
Gotta be able to
do a.45 in 25.
Did you time me?
沒有，我要打給羅絲太太
I did not and
I'm calling Albany.
那很愚蠢
That was stupid.
是嗎？
Was it?
你跟定我了
You're stuck with me,
Charlie.
沒有，我要走了
No, I'm not.
I'm outta here!
回新罕布夏？
Where you going,
New Hampshire?
怎麼回去？你沒錢
You got no money.
How you gonna do that?
凱倫的號碼嘗起來像在艾伯尼
Karen's number
tastes like Albany.
好吧，我走了
Fine.
I'm leaving.
查理！
Charlie. Charlie!
我只要你…
多陪我一天
All I want from you
is another day.
做什麼？
For what?
戰場最後的巡禮…
One last tour
of the battlefield.
紐約我很熟
I can get around
a city like New York,
但是…
but I
偶爾我需要有人指點方向
sometimes need a point
in the right direction.
如何，查理？
What do you say,
Charles?
陪朋友一天算得了什麼？
What's one day
between friends?
如果我多留一天…
你能把武器交給我嗎？
All right. Say I stay
for another day.
Will you give me
your weapon?
Oh, Charlie,
我是美國陸軍中校
I'm a lieutenant colonel,
United States Army.
我不把槍交給任何人
I'm not giving
my fucking gun
to anyone.
你要喝什麼？
Now, what are
you drinkin'?
中校，這種行為是不對的
Colonel, this
is unacceptable.
不對的？
少給我那套公子經！
Unacceptable?
What are you givin' me
that prep school crap for?
Unacceptable?
他們怎麼把你弄得
這麼沒人性
What have they done,
taken the Oregon
out of the boy?
答應你哈佛的獎學金是吧？
Put in Harvard
Business School?
不然把子彈給我
Then give me
your bullets.
你看穿我要自殺了？
You do see the sense of it,
Charlie, don't you?
我已形同廢物
I can't chew
the leather anymore.
為什麼要浪費糧食？
So, why should I share
the tribe's provisions?
我是說，沒有人…
I mean, there's no one
願意和我共渡良宵了
wants to tear a herring
with me anymore.
子彈給我，中校
The bullets, Colonel.
你聽來像「傲世軍魂」男主角
"The bullets, Colonel."
You sound like a guy in
Lives of a Bengal Lancer.
你才不關心呢？
What do you
give a shit for?
你指什麼？
About what?
什麼什麼？
我是不是把自己打的
腦袋開花
About whether
I blow my brains
out or not.
我有良心
Because I have
a conscience.
良心
You have
a conscience.
我竟然忘了
I forgot.
查理的良心
The Charlie Conscience.
要說？還是不說
Do we tell?
Do we not tell?
要不要聽從有錢少爺們？
Do we follow
the rich boy's code
or not?
要不要讓這瞎眼王八蛋…
Do we let this
blind asshole
去死？
die or not?
Yeah.
良心，查理
Conscience, Charlie.
你何時出生的？
When were
you born, son?
圓桌武士時代？
Around the time
of the Round Table?
你聽見我沒有？
Haven't you heard?
良心已死
Conscience is dead.
不，我沒聽說過
No, I haven't heard.
那就他媽的擦乾淨你耳朵
Then take the fucking wax
outta your ears!
長大！
Grow up!
滾你媽的蛋，小傢伙
It's fuck your buddy.
欺騙你太太
Cheat on your wife.
母親節打電話問候你媽
Call your mother
on Mother's Day.
Charlie,
都是狗屎
it's all shit.
你去哪裡
Where you goin'?
去尿尿
I got piss call.
雖然我說要你多留一天…
I know I said I need ya
forjust one day
我的尿可等不了那麼久
but even I can't
hold it that long.
查理！
Oh, and Charlie,
你忘了槍膛裡還有一粒
you forgot the one
in the chamber.
好了，先生
There you go, sir.
謝謝
Thank you.
服役26年
從沒讓助理擦過鞋
Twenty-six years
in the service,
never let an aide
shine my shoes.
26年後你會在哪裡？
Where you gonna be
in 26 years, Charlie?
和你博德的老友
打高爾夫吧
Playing golf with
your friends from
the Baird School, I bet.
我根本不喜歡他們
I don't even
like those guys.
你當然不喜歡
他們是王八蛋
Of course you don't.
They're all assholes.
能說出他們就好了
Be a pleasure to
squeal on 'em,
wouldn't it?
我不是告密的小人
Yeah, well,
I'm not a squealer.
「我不是告密的小人！」
"I'm not a squealer."
這是什麼？冤獄啊？
What is this,
the Dreyfus case?
哦，媽呀…
Ooh. Ooh, mama!
There you go.
Thank you.
小心
Watch your step.
我又有預感了，查理
I'm gettin' that heavy
feelin' again, Charlie.
這事還沒完呢
There's more to this,
isn't there?
不是嗎？
Isn't there?
有人賄賂我
I was offered
a bribe.
有點開竅了
Now we're cookin'.
校長垂斯克先生…
Mr. Trask,
the headmaster,
答應讓我進哈佛
he promised to get
me into Harvard.
只要你告密
If you squeal.
Yeah.
真是悲劇
What a dilemma.
查理西門
該不該搭便車進哈佛
Should Charlie Simms
accept a free ride
into Harvard, or not?
易地而處，喬治會怎麼辦？
What do you think your
friend George would do
if he were in your shoes?
他一定會的
怎麼說？
垂斯克先生
沒說要送他進哈佛
He is,
practically.
How?
It's just that Mr. Trask
hasn't promised to get
him into Harvard.
他不必要
喬治的爹會想辦法
Mr. Trask
doesn't have to.
George's father's
gonna take care
of that.
點頭吧，查理
進哈佛去
Do the deal,
Charlie. Take it!
Go to Harvard.
我不能這麼做
I can't do that.
為什麼不能？
Why not?
有些事你就是不能做
There are just
some things
you can't do.
解釋給我聽
Explain 'em to me.
大聲一點，拜託
Louder, please.
我不能…
I can't...
你在這世上可要吃苦頭了
You're gonna
have a tough time
in this world, Charlie.
為了讓你放輕鬆
請你喝一杯
走吧
To ease the blow,
let me buy you
a drink. Come on.
傑克丹尼爾加冰塊
Double
Jack Daniels on the rocks.
給我朋友一杯雪莉雞尾酒
And bring my
young friend here
a Shirley Temple.
等等，你有啤酒嗎？
Hold on.
Do you have beer?
當然有，你有證件嗎？
Certainly. May I
see some ID?
你想要一輩子當侍者？
Are you interested
in walkin' the rest
of your life, chappy?
抱歉，但是…
I'm sorry, sir, but...
我是這兒的常客
我孩子快廿三了
I'm a regular here.
My boy's going on 23.
你何不打電話問經理？
吉伯先生是我朋友
Why don't you
call up front,
the office?
Mr. Gilbert,
he's a friend of mine.
指定要哪個牌子嗎
Any particular beer?
「史利茲」，沒有的話
Schlitz. No Schlitz?
就要「布雷茲」
沒有「布雷茲」的話
Blatz. No Blatz?
就隨便了
Lmprovise.
一定讓您滿意
謝了
I'll do my best, sir.
Thank you, sir.
你總算像人了！喝啤酒呢！
You're human, Charlie.
Beer?
我們在跟誰一塊兒喝？
Who are we
drinking with?
上好香皂和水的清香
從那兒飄來
I'm getting
a nice soap-and-water
feeling from down there.
哦，女性
A female.
「女性」就表示你對她
有意思
"Female"?
You callin' her female
must mean you like her
or you wouldn't be so casual.
她一個人？
Is she alone?
一個人
Yeah, she's alone.
好戲要開鑼囉，栗色頭髮？
Things are heatin' up.
Chestnut hair?
棕色，淡棕色
Brown, light brown.
廿二？
我不太會猜年齡
Twenty-two?
What am I,
a guy at a carnival?
活到老，「泡」到老
The day we stop lookin',
Charlie, is the day we die.
行動
Move.
往哪？
你知道哪兒
Where?
You know where, son.
別害羞
Don't be coy, Charlie.
她是為你造的
我有預感
This woman is
made for you.
I can feel it.
漂亮死了吧？
Goddamn beautiful,
isn't she?
不壞
賓果！你還活著
She's not bad.
Bingo! The boy's alive.
來吧，孩子，大步走
Come on, son,
perambulate.
大步走
Perambulate.
打擾您了，小姐
介意我們和您同坐嗎？
Excuse me, se·orita,
do you mind if
we join you?
我有個您被忽視的感覺呢
I'm feelin' you're
being neglected.
我在等人
I'm expecting somebody.
他馬上就來？
Instantly?
不，但隨時會到
隨時會到
No, but any minute now.
Any minute?
有些人一分鐘內過盡一生
Some people live
a lifetime
in a minute.
現在你做什麼？
What are you doin'
right now?
我等他
I'm waiting for him.
介不介意我們陪你等？
Would you mind if
we waited with you,
好叫登徒子別煩你
just to keep
the womanizers
from bothering you?
不，我不介意
No, I don't mind.
謝謝
Thank you.
Charlie.
空氣中有香味兒
You know, I detect
a fragrance
in the air.
別告訴我什麼牌子
Don't tell me
what it is.
「歐吉維姐妹」香皂
Ogilvie Sisters
soap.
真不可思議！
That's amazing.
我做的正是不可思議之舉
I'm in the
amazing business.
正是「歐吉維姐妹」香皂
It is
Ogilvie Sisters
soap.
聖誕節祖母送我的
My grandmother gave me
three bars for Christmas.
我對你祖母著迷了！
她一定會喜歡查理
I'm crazy about
your grandmother.
I think she'd have
liked Charlie, too.
別理他
你的芳名是？
Don't pay any
attention to him.
What's your name?
唐娜
Donna.
唐娜，我是法蘭克
這位是…
Donna? I'm Frank.
This here is...
查理
Charlie.
她喜歡你
Yes.
She likes you.
查理有煩惱
他看來如何？
Charlie's having
a difficult weekend.
He's going
through a crisis.
How does he look like
he's holding up?
看來還好
He looks fine to me.
噢，她真的喜歡你
查理
She does like you,
Charlie.
好，唐娜…
So, Donna,
你跳探戈嗎？
do you tango?
以前想要學，但是…
No. I wanted to
learn once, but...
但是？
But?
麥可不想
But Michael
didn't want to.
麥可，你在等的人
Michael.
The one you're
waiting for.
麥可覺得探戈很可笑
Michael thinks
the tango's hysterical.
嗯，我想麥可很可笑
I think Michael's
hysterical.
別理他…
我好像說過了？
Don't pay any
attention to him.
Did I already
say that?
多美的笑聲
What a beautiful laugh.
謝謝，法蘭克
Thank you, Frank.
你想不想學探戈？
Would you like
to learn to tango,
Donna?
現在？
Right now?
免費服務，如何？
I'm offering you
my services,
free of charge.
What do you say?
我有點怕
I think I'd be
a little afraid.
怕什麼？
Of what?
踩錯步
Afraid of making
a mistake.
探戈裡無所謂錯步的
不像人生…
No mistakes
in the tango, Donna.
Not like life.
它簡單，所以才棒
It's simple.
That's what makes
the tango so great.
要是踏錯步或絆倒了
繼續跳
If you make a mistake,
get all tangled up,
just tango on.
何不試試？
Why don't you try?
好嗎？
Will you try it?
好，我試試
All right.
I'll give it a try.
扶住我，孩子
Hold me down, son.
你的手？
Your arm?
Charlie,
給我一點方位
I'm gonna need some
coordinates here, son.
舞池大約二十尺乘三十尺
你在舞池這邊
The floor's about
20 by 30,
and you're at
the long end.
外圍有些桌子…
樂隊也在那
There's some tables
on the outside and
the band's
on the right.
你跳的好極了！
Frank, you are
one incredible
dancer.
查理跳的才好呢
Wait'll you see
Charlie dance.
他撒謊，我不會跳
He's a liar.
I don't dance.
事實上，他不僅會跳
還能唱
Isn't he a charmer,
though?
Truth is,
not only can he dance,
but he'll sing you
a hell of a tune.
他會學鳥叫
還會模仿明星
He can do bird calls
and imitate Bela Lugosi.
Hi, honey.
Hi.
Hey.
麥可，這是法蘭克，查理
Michael, this is Frank
and this is Charlie.
抱歉我遲到了
Hi, Frank, Charlie.
Sorry I'm late.
沒關係
有兩位先生陪著我
That's okay.
These two gentlemen
entertained me,
時間一下子打發了
and time flew.
你女友的探戈跳得好極了
Your girl is a hell
of a tango dancer.
你總算找到人
陪你跳探戈了
At last,
you found someone
to tango with.
太棒了！
That's terrific!
我們握個手
Let me shake your hand.
不，是法蘭克陪我跳的
No, it was Frank.
那我握你們倆的手
Hell, I'll shake
both your hands!
親愛的，我們得走了
This looks like
the place, but
we gotta go.
和戴瑞和卡洛約好了
We got a date with
Darryl and Carol
in the Village.
帳單…
我的榮幸
Do you have a check?
Michael, please.
My pleasure.
不不，我來付
No, no. I got this.
把貴手拿開吧，我來
Michael, get your hand
outta your pocket.
I'll take it. Really.
讓我請吧
Allow me.
謝謝了，再會
Why, thank you.
Bye, guys.
Bye.
「戴瑞和卡洛」，是哦
Darryl and Carol.
Yeah.
17-E，她在等您呢
It's apartment 17E,
Colonel.
She's expecting you.
別擔心，她是最紅的
Don't worry about a thing.
She's the cr·me de la cr·me.
德國副議長找過她
現在他想移民呢
My buddy took
the Vice Chancellor
of Germany to her.
Now he wants to
immigrate to this country.
辦得好！
You did good, hombre.
我的頭髮，還好吧
My hair, how is it?
完美
It's perfect.
配紅領巾可以嗎？
I got the red
foulard okay,
didn't I?
是啊，深紅色
Yeah,
real dark red.
是葡萄酒色
她們愛死了！
Burgundy, Charlie.
Burgundy. They love it.
港灣刮鬍水
Bay rum.
溫莎結
Windsor knot.
摸摸我的心
That's my heart
I'm feelin'.
走了
I'm off.
可以打長途電話嗎？
Can you get long
distance on this?
請自便
And how. Be my guest.
「甘蔗叢」賓館
Sugarbush Lodge.
請接喬治威利斯
請稍等
Hi. George Willis, please?
One moment, please.
Hello?
Harry?
哈瑞？
小查，你好嗎？
Chas, how are you?
我們正要帶喬治去機場
You just caught us.
We're about to shoot
George over to the airport.
他為什麼要去機場？
慢著，你和他說吧
Why is George going
to the airport?
Hold on. Maybe
you should talk
to the man himself.
Chas.
嗨，喬治
Yeah. Hi, George.
晚一步我就走了
You just caught me.
我知道，你要去哪？
That's what Harry said.
Where you goin'?
回家
Home.
波士頓？
To Boston?
嗯，祝我好運
Catching the puddle·umper.
Keep your fingers crossed.
你回家做什麼？
What are you
going home for?
我想…
老垂也太不講理了
I was thinking.
This asshole, Trask?
He's making no sense at all.
得有人和他說說
我爸是五九年那屆的
Somebody's gotta talk to him.
My father was class of '59.
你爸爸？
我們約好不告訴父母的
Your father?
I thought we were gonna
keep our parents outta this.
老垂發瘋了！真瘋了
一定要有人出面
我爸又是主要捐款人
This guy Trask
is out of control, Chas.
Out of control!
Somebody's gotta
talk to him.
My father's
a major fundraiser,
you know.
我沒有說
No, I didn't.
別緊張，我爸會解決
我要走了，還好吧？
Right.
Relax. He'll get us
off the hook.
I gotta go.
Everything all right?
還好
Sure.
週一見，拜
I'll see you Monday.
Goodbye.
Bye.
Good night, sir.
Good night.
Hiya, Charlie.
Watch the door.
好漂亮的女人
What a beautiful woman.
哈囉
Hello, there.
你看到我看到了的？
Do you
see what I see?
是，有問題…
Yeah.
Either there's
something wrong,
不然就是我醉了
or we got the world's
worst hangover.
進來
Won't you come in?
銀行搶案的照片呢？
We hear
you got a picture of
the bank robbery.
中校？
Colonel?
你還好吧？
Colonel,
you all right?
幹嘛？
What is it?
下午了，一早上你都在睡
It's after noon.
You've been sleeping
all morning.
又怎樣？
So what?
沒什麼
I don't know.
I thought...
昨晚我和喬治通電話
他的…
I talked to George
last night.
他爸爸是很有勢力的校友
His father's a big-deal
alumnus at school.
He's got a lot of pull.
是嗎？
Really?
他要去和校長談
Yeah, he's gonna talk
to the headmaster.
喬治說他爸爸
能幫我們脫險
George thinks he might
be able to get us
off the hook.
「幫我們脫險」
"Get us off the hook."
他這麼說的
Yeah, that's what he said.
當心他所謂的「我們」
Watch the "us" part.
要不要去逛逛？
Colonel, don't you wanna
get up and do something?
Colonel?
查理，你要幹什麼？
Charlie, what do
you want?
不曉得，但是…
I don't know,
我被你弄的很緊張
but you're making
me nervous.
我的皮夾在抽屜裡
My wallet is
on the dresser.
拿走你的機票…
Take out your plane ticket
和四百塊錢
退伍津帖
and $400
mustering-out pay, plus
外加機場到學校的車資
airport-to-school taxi.
中校，不必急
Colonel, it's no rush.
I mean, I can...
我可以多待一會兒
I could stay for a while.
查理，你已給了我一天
Charlie, you already
gave me a day.
就為了那天，我永遠感激
And for that day,
I am eternally grateful.
但現在…
我另有計劃
But right now
I have other plans.
什麼計劃？
What other plans
do you have?
去死，孩子
To die, son.
中校，你…
Colonel, you're...
你今天可不准去死
Come on, Colonel,
you're not gonna die today.
查理，把你的手給我
Charlie,
give me your hand.
你走，好嗎？
You go now, boy.
Okay?
你走，留我一個…
You go. Just...
在這裡睡覺
Just leave me
sleep here.
我們再試試，好嗎？
Look...
Can we start
over, please?
你想做什麼？
What do you feel
like doin' today, huh?
你看，陽光燦爛
天氣美好
Look at this.
The sun is shining!
It's a beautiful day.
Let's...
你不會想掃我興致吧
Colonel, I know you don't
want to be a party poop,
我們出去活動一下
兜兜風
so let's go out
and do something.
Let's go for a ride.
對，兜兜風
Yeah, a ride.
兜風？
A ride?
嗯，好不好？
Yeah, Colonel Slade,
what do you say?
我們去兜風
Let's go
for a ride, huh?
哪一種兜風法？
What kind of ride?
嗯，這張駕照有效
Yeah, this is a valid
Oregon driver's license,
信得過的顧客可以試
泰德蘿莎
and we let appropriate
customers test-drive
the Testarossa.
你只有十七歲
同伴又失明
這我們無能為力
But you're 17, with
a blind companion.
That we don't do.
這車值十九萬
This is a $100,000
piece of machinery.
我不能讓它這樣出門
I'm not letting it
out this door.
那這部呢？
How about this one
over here?
那是加布雷提
That's a Cabriolet T.
The same deal.
我不能讓小孩開走
十一萬的車
You think I'll let
an unaccompanied kid
get in a $110,000 car?
他會有伴的
He will not be
unaccompanied.
我會和他一起試車
我是他父親
I'll be with him.
I'm his father.
你是他父親？
You're his father?
Yes.
這樣吧
我帶你父親去試車
I have an idea. Why don't
I take your father
for a test drive?
你的業績要多少？
What's your quota, Freddie?
不勞費心
Don't worry
about my quota.
I do well.
這個月你賣了幾輛法拉利？
How many Ferraris
you sold this month?
數目不重要
八０年代結束了
That's not relevant
to this discussion.
Freddie,
the '·0s are over.
這些奢侈品不好送出門吧？
Are you tryin' to tell me
these things are walkin'
outta the store?
這可是法拉利哦
汽車界的最佳出品
This is a Ferrari, sir,
the finest machinery made
in the automobile industry.
你要那麼喜歡它
何不跟它睡
If you like it that much,
why don't you sleep with it?
Why are you sellin' it?
我很願意幫忙，但是…
I'd love to
accommodate you...
如果它符合我的期望…
If this car performs
the way I expect it to,
你會拿到一張
十萬一千元的支票
you will get
a check of $101,000,
and change,
就明天一早！
when you come in
here tomorrow morning.
售價是十萬九千九百
五十塊，外加稅
It's $100,000,
plus $050,
plus tax.
佛迪，為了你…
Freddie, for you
我加到十萬七千元
107 all in,
外送一箱香檳
讓你配剩火雞喝
plus a case of champagne
to go with your
leftover turkey.
如何？別擔心這孩子
What do you say?
Don't worry about
the boy.
他開得穩的可以在引擎上煮蛋
He drives so smooth,
you can boil an egg
on the engine.
還車的時候，我來剝蛋
When we bring
the car back, I'll peel
the egg for ya.
你把我逗笑了
但車不能給你
Listen, you made me laugh,
but I can't let
the car go out.
要不要押金？
Want a deposit?
我們不搞分期付款的
先生
This is not an
installment item, sir.
你又不是生手
Freddie, you're
no spring chicken.
你知道同事叫我什麼嗎？
老黑爵
為什麼還留我呢？
You know what they call me
at the home office?
"The Grey Ghost."
You know why they
still keep me around?
因為後生小輩
賣不掉法拉利
There's no kid here
that can move a Ferrari
like I can.
從東岸到西岸人盡皆知
I'm known from
coast to coast
like butter and toast.
Ask anybody about
Freddie Bisco.
進來一部…
我就賣掉一部
When I get a Ferrari...
Out the door!
你才逗我笑呢，佛迪
You just made
me laugh, Freddie.
Yeah?
兩千塊
2,000.
你不拿，我可要哭了
Unless you take it,
you're gonna make me cry.
我也是老黑爵
I'm a grey ghost, too.
看吧？
很過癮吧？
See? This is fun,
isn't it?
放空檔
推二檔，放離合器
Drop her into neutral.
Slide her into second.
Pop the clutch.
開直
就這樣開，直點
Straight.
Hold it right
like that.
Feel it?
That's straight.
It's a straight street,
so keep it straight.
開直
Keep it straight.
開直就沒意思了
No fun just
to keep it straight.
要猛一點才夠勁
You've got to move
a little bit,
feel the road.
拜託，就這麼開，好嗎？
Please? Just like this.
All right? There you go.
穩穩的
Take it nice and easy.
喜歡嗎？
Do you like this?
放慢點，開太快了
Slow it down
a little, Colonel.
You're goin' a little fast.
中校，放慢點
Colonel, slow it down.
我的腳出問題了
Something's happened
to my foot!
慢點，拜託
Slow it down, please.
分明有另一檔可以用
Hold on. I think
I've got another gear.
史中校！
Colonel Slade?
Hoo-ah!
看路！
Watch out!
你要害我們送命！
You'll get us killed!
別怪我，我看不到
Don't blame me,
Charlie, I can't see!
中校，慢點
天啊，耶穌基督
Colonel,
slow it down!
Oh, Jesus!
看看這個寶貝怎麼轉彎
Now let's see how
this baby corners.
轉彎？
Corners?
對啊，給我信號
Yeah. Say when.
什麼？
Say when what?
轉彎信號
Say when to turn.
你不能轉彎
Colonel,
you can't turn the car.
在哪轉，查理？
Where's
the turn, Charlie?
三點鐘方位？兩點
右？歪？
3 o'clock? 2 o'clock?
Right oblique? Right face?
快啊，說啊
Come on! Talk to me!
左
It's left, I guess.
我知道轉左，現在？
Left. I knew it. Okay. Now?
不是不是！
No, no! Not now! Not now!
現在？
Now?
拜託
Colonel, please!
我要轉了
I'm gonna do it anyway,
all right?
不管你同不同意
Whether you say so
or not, here we go!
好，等等
等一下
Okay! Wait, wait, wait!
Just wait!
我要轉了…要轉了…
Here I go.
慢著
轉！
Wait... Now!
我轉成了！噢，查理！
I did it! Charlie!
你的同伴很快樂！
You're ridin' with
one very happy man!
你還得再轉
Turn again!
要仔細
Be specific, son.
向左，轉！
Left now!
Okay.
愛死這遊戲了！
愛死了！
I love this! I love it!
試試最高速
Shall we take it to the max?
我要下車
Let me out.
媽的！條子
Shit!
The yellow flag.
我還沒開始衝呢
I haven't even
opened her up yet.
Which way's the curb?
靠邊停，放慢，中校
Pull over. Slow down!
Slow down.
好吧，來了
I'm doin' it.
放慢
Pull over to
the curb, here.
Slow down.
我知道
Yep. Got it.
我幾年來都沒拿罰單
Haven't had
a ticket in years.
我來應付
I'll do the talking.
駕照和車牌
License
and registration.
在試這部小寶貝？
Are you test-driving
this baby?
很神吧？
Don't she purr, though?
時速七十英哩？
At 70 miles an hour?
你該看看她一百廿五的英姿
You should hear
her at 125.
駕照呢？
Where's your license?
在車行
還車的時候才拿
At the dealer's.
They give it back
when you return the car.
你有身份證？
You got ID?
可不是
You bet.
在此
Indeed.
史雷德中校
Lieutenant Colonel Slade.
你呢，警員？
And you, soldier?
我是高爾警官
The name is
Police Officer Gore.
你執勤認真
Doin' a hell
of a job, Gore.
你也不差，中校
And so are you,
Colonel.
小孩是誰？
Who's the kid?
小犬，查理
My boy Charlie.
一直叫我開她出來
能讓他失望嗎？
He kept tellin' me
to "let her out."
What was I gonna do,
disappoint him?
當然
Yes.
這麼辦吧…
Tell you what
I'm gonna do,
Colonel.
我放你一馬，但有個條件
I'm gonna let you go,
on one condition.
什麼？
What's that?
馬上把車送回車行
That you take this rig
straight back to the dealer.
沒問題
You got it.
閉嘴
Shut up.
要這個嗎？
You want this?
當然
Sure.
高爾
Gore?
你的臉孔和聲音我很熟
Your face and
your voice
are familiar.
加入過丹納的軍官俱樂部嗎？
You ever been
in the officer's
club at Da Nang?
沒有
No.
也沒進過陸軍
Never in the Army?
沒有，海岸防衛隊而已
No. Coast Guard.
老天
Good Lord.
你爸氣色不錯，查理
Your dad
is looking good,
Charlie.
就是喜歡開快車…
勸他開慢點
He's got a heavy foot, though.
Tell him to take it light,
all right?
知道了
I hear ya!
All right.
Thanks.
下車，不准你再開了
Get out of the car,
because you are not
driving anymore.
我在暖車罷了
Just keeping this baby
warm, that's all.
我不開了
I'm not drivin' anymore.
Yes.
扶著我的肩膀
Take my arm.
I'm okay.
路不平
Colonel,
it's really
bumpy here.
還好吧？
You all right?
Yeah.
紅燈，中校，別走
Red light. Hold it.
等太久了
Taking too long.
Shit! Colonel! Colonel!
Colonel!
沒事吧？
Shit! You all right?
你幹什麼你？拿好拐杖啊
What the hell
are you doing?
Take the cane.
我要尿尿
拿好拐杖
I gotta take a piss.
Take the cane.
小便不能忍
Happens to
the best of us.
不能在公園大道尿啊
最好不過
We're on
Park Avenue.
You can't.
Perfect place.
警察會抓你的
You'll get arrested.
我從來不亂尿
Never been
housebroken.
Colonel!
Shit!
你到底怎麼搞的？
What's the matter
with you, Colonel?
你在幹嘛？
快起來
What are you doing?
Stand up.
別亂來
Come on.
我好累，查理
I'm tired, Charlie.
I'm tired.
讓我握你手臂
Give me your arm.
你的拐杖
Here's your cane.
帶我回旅館，孩子
Take me back
to the hotel, son.
總算到家了
Home at last.
你還好吧？
You all right now?
Yeah.
要不要上廁所？
Do you want to
use the bathroom?
不要
No.
需要什麼嗎？
不要
Can I get you
something?
No.
你真的沒事？
我很好
You sure you're
all right?
I'm fine, Charlie.
我可以打電話嗎？
Do you mind if
I use the phone?
打吧
Go ahead.
Hello?
請問喬治在嗎？
Hi, is George there,
please?
小喬還是老喬？
Senior or Junior?
小喬
Junior.
哪位？
Who's this?
他學校的朋友
A friend of his
from school.
他不能跟任何朋友講話了
Sorry, but George isn't going
to be talking to any friends
from school right now.
Oh.
Goodbye.
你在瞪我嗎？
Colonel, are you
looking at me?
我是個瞎子，查理
I'm blind, Charlie.
我要去睡一會兒
I'm gonna take a nap.
兜風太久
Too much fresh air.
那好
It's probably a good idea.
我扶你進房
Want me to help you
to your room?
不必
No.
我睡沙發
Couch.
我喜歡這張
I like this couch here.
你真的沒事？
You sure you're
all right, Colonel?
我頭痛
I got a headache.
下樓去替我買阿斯匹靈吧
Why don't you go
downstairs, get me
some aspirin?
好
另外…
Some aspirin.
Yeah. Also...
再帶根雪茄
I feel like a cigar.
蒙地奎斯特一號的
Get me a couple of
Montecristos Number One.
蒙地奎斯特一號
Montecristos
Number One.
Yeah.
樓下小店不會有
You won't be able
to get 'em at
the newsstand downstairs.
那你就過街…
So why don't you
go over to
到街口的唐喜商店買
50th and Fifth,
Dunhill's.
叫阿諾的在掌櫃
Fella named Arnold there,
in the humidor.
告訴他是我要的
Tell him
they're for me.
他知道的
He'll know.
回來的太快了吧？
You're back
too fast.
你一定沒替我買雪茄？
You didn't get
my cigars, did you?
滾開，查理
Get out of
here, Charlie.
我們已經講清楚了
I thought we had a deal.
我毀約
我愛毀約，沒告訴過你？
I welched.
I'm a welcher.
Didn't I tell you?
你說要把所有子彈給我
No, what you told me
was that you gave me
all the bullets.
騙你的
I lied.
你是把我騙住了
You could have fooled me.
可不是
And I did.
沒有我，你怎麼辦啊？
How you ever
gonna survive in this
world without me?
把槍給我好嗎？
Why don't you just
give me the gun,
all right?
你幹什麼？
What are you doing?
我也會一槍打死你
I'm gonna
shoot you, too.
反正你已經完了
Your life's
finished anyway.
喬治會見風轉舵
你也一樣完蛋
Your friend George
is going to sing
like a canary.
And so are you.
一旦如此，查理寶寶…
And once you've sung,
Charlie, my boy,
你在那乏味的成人隊伍中
you're gonna take
your place on that
long, gray line
就佔有一席之地了…
of American manhood.
你也就完了
And you will
be through.
我不苟同
I'd like to disagree
with you, Colonel.
你沒資格不苟同
四五手槍在我手裡
你只有粉刺
You're in no
position to disagree
with me, boy.
I got a loaded.45 here.
You got pimples.
我要把你殺了…
I'm gonna
kill ya, Charlie,
因為我不能忍受看著你去…
because I can't
bear the thought
出賣原則
of you sellin' out!
把槍放下
Put the gun down,
all right, Colonel?
什麼？
你在下最後通牒？
What? You givin' me
an ultimatum?
No, I'm...
最後通牒由我來下！
I give the ultimatums!
抱歉
I'm sorry.
我道歉
All right? I'm sorry.
我也道歉
It's all right,
查理
Charlie.
你傷了我的心，孩子
You break
my heart, son.
我這一生…
All my life
I stood up
反抗任何人，所有事…
to everyone
and everything,
只有這樣，我才覺得…
自己重要
because it made me
feel important.
但你卻是為了
你的原則而反抗
You do it
'cause you mean it.
你很正直
You got
integrity, Charlie.
我不曉得該打死你
還是收養你
I don't know whether to
shoot you or adopt you.
很為難，是吧？
Not much of a choice,
is it, sir?
少耍嘴皮子
Don't get cute now.
請把槍放下
Could you please
put the gun away?
我在問你問題
I asked you
a question.
你要不要我收養你？
Do you want me
to adopt you,
or don't you?
請放下槍…
Please? I mean...
你只是情緒低落
You're just in a slump
right now.
情緒低落？
Slump?
不是，查理
No slump, Charlie.
我是壞人
I'm bad.
不，我不很壞
I'm not bad. No.
我爛掉了
I'm rotten.
你不壞
You're not bad.
只是痛苦而已
You're just in pain.
你懂什麼叫痛苦？
What do you know
about pain?
你只不過是大海裡的一隻小魚
You little snail darter
from the Pacific Northwest.
你媽的懂什麼叫痛苦？
Fuck you know
about pain?
把槍給我
Let me have the gun,
Colonel.
想充大人不容易，孩子
No time to grow
a dick, son.
請把槍給我，中校
Just give me the gun,
all right, Colonel?
你最好別動
I'm talkin' a
parade ground.
立正！
Ten-hut!
小兵，那可是命令
Soldier, that was
a direct order.
槍給我
Give me the gun.
要走要留隨便你
You can stay or
you can leave.
懂嗎？
You understand?
反正我會用到這玩意兒
Either way, I'm gonna
do this thing.
現在，你何不避開點
Now why don't
you leave and
spare yourself?
給我槍，中校
I want your gun,
Colonel.
我自己來計時
I'm gonna give
myself a count.
計時有助平衡
You need a count
for balance.
五、四…
Five...
Four...
三…
Three...
二…
Two...
一
One...
幹！
Fuck it.
給我！
Give me! Fuck!
滾出去！
我不走！
Get out of here!
I'm stayin' right here!
滾開！
Get outta here!
我不走！
I'm stayin' right here.
我射爛你腦袋！
I'll blow your
fuckin' head off!
射呀！你要射就射
快啊！
Then do it!
You want to do it?
Do it! Let's go.
滾蛋！
Get outta here!
你搞砸了，又怎樣呢？
You fucked up,
all right? So what?
人人都會犯錯
你該勇往直前啊
So everybody does it.
Get on with your life,
would ya?
直什麼前？
What life?
我早完了！
I got no life!
我活在黑暗裡
I'm in the dark here!
你明白嗎？
You understand?
活在黑暗裡！
I'm in the dark!
那放棄算了！
儘管自暴自棄吧
我也要放棄了
So give up.
You want to give up, give up.
Because I'm givin' up, too.
你講的對，我完了
You said I'm through.
You're right,
I am through.
我們都完了，沒希望了
We're both through.
It's all over.
媽的就幹吧！
So let's get on with it.
Let's fuckin' do it.
扣他媽的扳機…
Let's fuckin'
pull the trigger,
你這不可理喻的瞎子！
you miserable
blind motherfucker.
扣啊！
Pull the trigger.
預備了…
Here we go, Charlie.
我好了
I'm ready.
你不想死
You don't want to die.
你也不想
And neither do you.
再給我一個理由
Give me one
reason not to.
我給你兩個，
你跳探戈和開法拉利帥極了
I'll give you two.
You can dance the tango
and drive a Ferrari better
than anyone I've ever seen.
你以前沒看過吧
You never seen
anyone do either.
把槍給我，中校
Give me the gun,
Colonel.
我該怎麼辦，查理？
Where do I go
from here, Charlie?
「煩心就跳探戈」
If you're tangled up,
just tango on.
你要請我跳舞？
You askin' me
to dance, Charlie?
「你從沒想過要翩然離去？」
Did you ever
have the feelin'
That you wanted to go
「心裡又渴望留下」
And still had the feelin'
that you wanted to stay?
你喜歡我的藍制服？
You like my blues,
Charlie?
很漂亮
Yeah, they're beautiful.
我穿它們…
I wore these
參加詹森的就職大典
for Lyndon's
inauguration.
當然啦…
我們不是最重要的來賓
Of course, we weren't
the number one ball.
但他過來打招呼了
But he dropped by
anyway.
請把槍給我
Will you please
give me the gun?
你在要求一個軍官…
You're askin' an officer
繳出他的武器
to surrender his sidearm.
你不必「繳出」
放下就好了
You don't have
to surrender it.
Just put it down
for a little while.
放下來吧
All right?
Just put it down.
我需要喝一杯
Boy, I could use
a drink, Charlie.
咖啡好嗎？
How about a cup of coffee?
我要三思而行
查理
Too big a leap for me
right now, Charlie.
也許明天再死
Maybe tomorrow.
不
還是來杯傑克丹尼爾吧
No, a Mr. John Daniels
would be preferred.
別摻水，查理
No water,
Charlie.
不摻水
No water.
麻煩你了
Please.
你的酒
對不起
Here's your drink,
Colonel.
Oh, I'm so sorry.
什麼時候幫你鋪床？
What time do you want me
to turn down the bed?
等會兒吧
Maybe later,
all right?
他的意思是，小姐…
What he means,
se·orita,
坐過來
is come right in.
等會兒
Later, please?
是的，午安
Yes, sir.
Good afternoon.
聲音不賴
Nice voice.
你老想著一件事
Boy, you have
a one-track mind.
這世上還有別的事嗎？
Is there anything else
in this world, Charlie?
對你可沒有
Not for you.
你知道我前進的動力嗎？
You know what's
kept me goin'
all these years?
就是夢想…
The thought
有一天…
that one day...
算了
Never mind.
什麼？
The what?
很笨
Silly.
就是夢想也許有一天…
Just the thought that
maybe one day, I'd...
能有女人雙臂抱著我…
I could have a woman's arms
wrapped around me,
雙腿纏著我…
and her legs
wrapped around me.
然後呢？
And what?
早晨我睜開眼睛而她還在
That I could wake up
in the morning and
she'd still be there.
她的味道…
Smell of her.
甜膩而溫暖
All funky and warm.
後來我就死心了
I finally gave up on it.
我不懂這為什麼不可能
我們回新罕布夏以後
我們來物色
I don't know why
you can't have that.
When we get back
to New Hampshire,
I don't know why you
can't find someone.
你這麼帥，而且…
You're a good-lookin' guy
你很風趣…
又是旅途良伴
and you're fun to be with
and you're a great
travel companion,
你敏感，富同情心
sensitive, compassionate.
查理，你在逗我是吧？
Charlie,
are you fuckin' with me?
是啊
Yes.
喂
我們錯過班機了
Yeah?
Hey, Manny.
We missed our plane.
你的班機，查理
我的機票是單程
Your plane, Charlie.
My ticket was one-way.
走新英格蘭大道？
New England thruway
all the way, Colonel?
一路到底
All the way,
Manolo.
我的預感又來了
I'm gettin' that heavy
feelin' again, Charlie.
Uh...
"Uh..."
我想你對喬治父子的看法很對
I think you were
right about George
and his father.
真遺憾
I'm sorry
to hear that.
回去以後
垂斯克會叫我們出列
When we get back Mr. Trask
is bringing us up
in front of the whole school.
「抓你的腳到火堆前」
Puttin' your feet
to the fire?
生活委員會召開的
特別會議
Special meeting of the
disciplinary committee.
你要怎麼說？
And what are you
gonna tell 'em?
我會找些話題
I don't know.
I'll think of somethin'.
查理，你怎麼會落單呢？
Charlie, why are you
all alone in this thing?
你爸爸在哪裡？
Where's your father?
走了
He left.
我以為你家的店是父母開的
誰是爸爸？
I thought it was a
mom-and-pop store.
Who's the pop?
我繼父
It's my stepfather.
Oh, yeah.
他怎麼不管這事？
他有毛病？
But why isn't
he in on this?
Somethin' wrong with him?
沒有
我們只是處不來而已
No, he's okay. We just...
We don't get along
very well.
為什麼？
Why not?
他是混球
倒也無妨
Because he's
an asshole.
Well, that's
all right, Charlie.
每家都有一個
Every family's
got one nowadays.
就這些？
That's it?
就這些
That's it.
保重
好，謝了
Take care of
yourself, kid.
All right, Manny.
Thanks.
不，我不開窗
No,
I'm not opening.
我痛恨道別
I hate goodbyes.
你不會有事吧？
So...
You'll be
all right, huh?
不會
I'll be fine.
那好
All right.
什麼玩意？
What's that?
預備鈴
That's first bell.
剛好夠我梳洗
Just got time
to get cleaned up.
我差點忘了
I almost forgot.
我還欠你錢
I owe you
some money.
三百塊
順利完工
$300.
Job well done.
需要推薦信的話，來找我
You ever need
any references, Charlie,
I'm your man.
謝謝，中校
Thanks, Colonel.
華特街十六號，過橋就到
16 Water Street.
Over the bridge.
我知道路
We'll find it.
再會，查理
Goodbye, Charlie.
再見，中校
Goodbye, Colonel.
來，查理
Come here, son.
好了，曼尼
Okay, Manny.
喬治…
George. George!
我召開這次會議
I called an open meeting
of this institution
this morning
因為上週二發生的事件
because the incident
that occurred this
Tuesday last
關係到我們全體
describes an issue
that concerns all of us.
那不是單純的塗鴨
Not an isolated case
of vandalism.
而是我們社會的病態表徵
What happened
is a symptom
of the sickness
of a society.
並與博德的立校精神…
嚴重衝突
A sickness which runs
counter to the principles
this school was founded on.
本校的畢業生中
A school among
whose graduates
兩個曾入主白宮
two have sat behind the
desk in the Oval O·ce,
in the White House.
博德的人掌管州政府
投資局
Baird men have
run State Departments
and investment houses,
興建百貨商場…
指導足球隊
founded department stores
and coached football teams.
我們的校友在印度僧舍…
Our alumni receive
their bulletins in
ashrams in India
及約旦皇宮中都有
我們被視為
「國家領袖的搖籃」
and in palaces in Jordan.
We are, in fact,
known around the world
as the cradle of this
country's leadership.
你怎麼會在這裡？
台上有沒有位子？
A beacon in the...
What are you doing here?
Got room for me
up there, Charlie?
今天
我們因受辱而蒙羞
But today we are bleeding
from disrespect.
應該有
幫我一把
Yeah, I guess so.
Blatant disrespect.
Give us a hand.
不尊重本校價值觀…
A disrespect
for our values,
也不尊重
我們的標準
and a disrespect
for our standards.
更不尊重博德傳統
為了護衛該傳統…
A disrespect for
the Baird tradition.
And, as the custodians
of that tradition,
今天我們齊聚一堂…
保衛它不受摧殘
we are here today
to protect each other
from those who threaten it.
這是哪位，西門先生？
Who is this, Mr. Simms?
法蘭克.史雷德先生
This is Mr. Frank Slade,
美國陸軍中校，退役
Lieutenant Colonel,
United States Army,
retired.
我代表查理父母出席
I'm here in place
of Charlie's parents.
抱歉？
Excuse me?
「代表他父母」
In loco parentis.
他們不能從奧勒岡趕來
They could not make
the trip from
Oregon today.
您和西門先生是什麼關係？
And what is your
relationship to Mr. Simms?
這是法庭嗎？
Is this a
courtroom?
是最接近法庭的安排
Closest thing
we could manage to it.
如果要發誓
我倒想和幾個人一起
Then if we're taking oaths,
there's a few people
I'd like to swear in.
在博德是不發誓的
There are no oaths
at Baird.
我們自律
We are all on our honor.
拉瑞和芬妮
是我很好的朋友
Larry and Franny Simms
are very dear,
close friends of mine.
他們拜託我來
They've asked me
to appear here on
Charlie's behalf.
行嗎？
Okay?
歡迎光臨
Happy to have you
with us, Colonel.
威利斯先生
Mr. Willis.
哪一位？
Which Mr. Willis?
喬治二世，先生
George, Junior, sir.
Yes.
你目睹了塗鴨事件的經過
是誰做的？
You were in a position
last Tuesday night
to see who committed
this act of vandalism.
Who was it?
嗯，我不曉得是誰
Well, I have an idea
who it was.
不曉得
No, not an idea,
Mr. Willis.
你看到或沒看到？
Did you see or
did you not see?
Well...
我沒戴隱形眼鏡
I didn't have
my contacts in.
Come on.
在圖書館的時候脫下的
I was in the library.
I'd taken my glasses off,
本來要再戴回去
and I was gonna put
my contacts back in.
我幫西門鎖門
Then I helped
Simms close up
之後，我們已經在外面了
and the next thing
I know, we're outside,
我聽到聲音…
and I hear
this sound and I
但是沒時間戴隱形眼鏡
didn't have any time
to put my contacts in.
在你有限的視力下你看到誰
Whom, with your
limited vision,
did you see?
我講過了，看不清楚
Like I say,
it was blurry.
沒戴眼鏡我看不到
I can't see
without my contacts.
你看到誰，威利斯先生？
What did you see,
Mr. Willis?
你是說，確定地？
What?
You mean definitively?
不要閃爍其詞
講清楚
Stop fencing with me,
Mr. Willis!
Tell me what you saw!
不要全信我的話
不過…
沒眼鏡，天又黑…
Now, don't hold me to this,
but no contacts, it's dark...
等等…
And everything, I mean...
Mr. Willis!
可能是…
Maybe...
哈瑞.海夫曼爾
Harry Havemeyer,
博德.波特
和吉米.詹姆森
Trent Potter and
Jimmy Jameson.
「可能」？
Maybe?
猜測而已，我盡力了
Ballpark, best guess.
能提供一點細節嗎？
Could you provide us
with some detaiI?
何不問查理？他站的更近
Why don't you ask Charlie?
I really think he was closer.
西門先生
Mr. Simms.
Yes.
你沒戴隱形眼鏡吧？
You don't wear contact lenses,
do you?
沒有，先生
No, sir.
在你無礙的視野內
With your
untrammeled sight,
你看到誰了？
w£om did you see?
我是看到一些人
Well, I saw something,
但不能講是誰
but I couldn't say who.
你看到的是什麼？
All right. What was
the something you saw?
我不能說
I couldn't say.
不能說或不想說？
You couldn't or wouldn't say?
不，我只是…
Well, I just...
我不能說
不能、不想、不該
I just couldn't say.
Couldn't, wouldn't, shouldn't.
你磨盡我的耐性
還愚弄了大家
You're exhausting my patience
and making a mockery
of these proceedings.
我給你最後一次機會
西門先生
I will give you
one last chance.
The consequences
of your response
will be dire.
你的回答將決定你的未來
By dire, I mean
your future will be
jeopardized permanently.
現在，最後一次問你…
Now for the last time,
上週二晚上你看到誰在停車場
w£at did you see
last Tuesday night
outside my office?
我看到某些人
I saw somebody.
「我看到某些人」，好
"I saw somebody." Good.
看到他們的身材面貌了？
Did you see their
size and shape?
Yeah.
是誰的身材，面貌？
And they were the size
and shape of whom?
那些特徵…
They were the size and shape
看來像任何博德學生
先生
of most any
Baird student, sir.
我竟沒有一個證人！
I am left with
no real witness.
威利斯先生的證詞
模糊不清
Mr. Willis' testimony
is not only vague,
it is unsubstantiated.
我所尋找的線索
西門先生
The substance I was
looking for, Mr. Simms,
應該來自於你
was to come from you.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
我也很抱歉，西門先生
我既不能處罰…
海夫曼爾先生、波特先生
或詹姆森先生
I'm sorry, too, Mr. Simms,
because you know
what I'm going to do
inasmuch as I can't
punish Mr. Havemeyer
Mr. Potter or Mr. Jameson?
我也不會處罰威利斯先生
And I won't punish
Mr. Willis.
他是唯一配稱
「博德人」的份子
He's the only party
to this incident
w£o is still worthy
of calling himself
a Baird man.
我將建議生活委員會…
I'm going to recommend to
the disciplinary committee
開除你
that you be expelled.
你隱瞞真相…
又撒謊
Mr. Simms, you are
a cover-up artist
and you are a liar.
但不出賣朋友
But not a snitch!
請你重覆一遍
Excuse me?
我說得很清楚
No, I don't think
I will.
Mr. Slade.
這場聽證會簡直是胡鬧
This is such
a crock of shit!
請小心措詞
Please watch
your language, Mr. Slade.
你身在博德，不是軍營
You are in the Baird school,
not a barracks.
西門先生
我給你最後機會
Mr. Simms, I will
give you one final
opportunity to speak up.
西門先生不需要
Mr. Simms
doesn't want it.
他不需要被帖上
「博德人」標誌
He doesn't need
to be labeled
"still worthy of
being a Baird man."
這算什麼？
What the hell is that?
你們的座右銘是什麼？
What is your motto here?
「孩子們，出賣朋友求自保」
"Boys, inform on
your classmates,
save your hide,
「否則讓你屍骨無存」
"anything short of that,
we're gonna burn you
at the stake?"
先生們…
Well, gentlemen,
出紕漏時
有人跑，有人留
when the shit hits the fan,
some guys run,
and some guys stay.
查理面對困難
那邊的喬治卻躲進老爹的口袋裡
Here's Charlie,
facin' the fire,
and there's George,
hidin' in big daddy's pocket.
結果你做什麼呢？
And what are you doin'?
你獎勵喬治，開除查理
You're gonna reward George
and destroy Charlie.
你講完了，史先生？
Are you finished,
Mr. Slade?
不，我才剛暖好身
No, I'm just gettin'
warmed up.
我不知道誰念過博德
威廉塔夫脫、威廉布萊恩…
威廉泰爾…等等
I don't know
who went to
this place.
William Howard Taft,
William Jennings Bryan,
William Tell, whoever.
他們精神已死
就算曾有現在也沒了
Their spirit is dead,
if they ever had one.
It's gone.
你在這裡培育的是老鼠大隊
You're buildin'
a rat ship here,
一堆賣友求榮的告密者
a vessel for
seagoin' snitches.
如果你以為在鍛煉
蝦兵成龍頭
And if you think
you're preparin' these
minnows for manhood,
你最好三思
you better think again,
因為你正扼殺了…
because I say you are
killin' the very spirit
這所學府所堅持的精神
this institution
proclaims it instills.
真是恥辱
What a sham.
你們今天給我看的是什麼秀？
What kind of a show
are you guys puttin'
on here today?
唯一有格調的人
坐在我旁邊！
The only class
in this act is
sittin' next to me.
我可以告訴你
這孩子的靈魂沒有被污染
And I'm here
to tell you this boy's
soul is intact.
而且無庸置疑
為什麼我知道？
It's non-negotiable.
You know how I know?
這裡有人…我不說他是誰
要收買他
Someone here,
and I won't say who,
offered to buy it.
但查理不為所動
你太過份了
Only Charlie
here wasn't sellin'.
Sir, you're
out of order.
我告訴你什麼叫過份
I'd show you
out of order.
你根本不知道什麼叫過份
You don't know what
out of order is,
Mr. Trask.
我很想示範
但我太老、太累又瞎了
I'd show you,
but I'm too old,
I'm too tired,
I'm too fuckin' blind.
如果是五年前
我會帶火焰噴射槍來這兒！
If I were the man I was
five years ago, I'd take
a flamethrower to this place!
你以為你在跟誰說話？
Out of order? Who the hell
you think you're talkin' to?
我是見過世面的
明白嗎？
I've been around, you know?
有一度，我還看得見…
There was a time
I could see.
我見過很多更年輕的男孩
And I have seen.
Boys like these,
younger than these,
臂膀被扭斷，雙腿被炸斷
their arms torn out,
their legs ripped off.
但那些都不及醜陋的靈魂可怕
But there is nothin'
like the sight
of an amputated spirit.
靈魂不可能有義肢
There is no prosthetic
for that.
你以為你只是…
把這好青年
像落荒狗似的送回家
You think you're merely
sendin' this splendid
foot soldier
back home to Oregon with
his tail between his legs,
我說你是處死了他的靈魂
but I say you are
executin' his soul!
為什麼？
And why?
因為他不是博德人
Because he's not
a Baird man.
博德人
傷了這男孩，你就是博德孬種
Baird men.
You hurt this boy,
you're gonna be Baird bums,
the lot of you.
而哈瑞、吉米、博德…
And, Harry, Jimmy,
不管你們坐在哪裡…
Trent, wherever you are
out there,
去你媽的！
fuck you, too!
坐下，史雷德先生
Stand down, Mr. Slade!
我還沒講完
I'm not finished.
來這兒的時候…
我聽到類似
「領袖搖籃」的字眼
As I came in here,
I heard those words,
"cradle of leadership."
當支幹斷掉時
搖籃就垮了
它已經垮了，已經垮了
Well, "when the bough breaks,
the cradle will fall,"
and it has fallen here.
It has fallen.
人類製造者、領袖創造家
Makers of men,
creators of leaders.
當心你創造的是哪種領袖
Be careful what
kind of leaders
you're producin' here.
我不知道…
查理今天的緘默是對是錯
I don't know if Charlie's
silence here today
is right or wrong.
I'm not a judge orjury.
但我可以告訴你…
But I can tell you this,
他絕不會出賣別人
以求前程
he won't sell anybody out
to buy his future!
朋友們，這就叫正直
And that, my friends,
is called integrity.
也叫勇氣
That's called courage.
那才是領袖的要件
Now that's the stuff
leaders should be made of.
每次我走到人生十字路口
Now I have come to
the crossroads in my life.
我總是知道哪條路是對的
I always knew what
the right path was.
毫無例外，我就知道
但我從不走，為什麼？
Without exception, I knew,
but I never took it.
You know why?
因為那他媽的太苦了
It was too damn hard.
而現在查理
他也走到了十字路口
Now here's Charlie.
He's come to
the crossroads.
他選擇了對的路
He has chosen a path.
It's the right path.
一條磨練領袖個性的道路
It's a path made of principle
that leads to character.
讓他繼續他的行程吧
Let him continue
on his journey.
他的未來掌握在您手中
委員們
You hold this boy's future
in your hands, committee.
那是個價值連城的未來
It's a valuable future,
相信我
believe me.
別毀了它，保護它
Don't destroy it.
Protect it.
擁抱它
Embrace it.
我保證有一天您會引以為傲
It's gonna make you
proud one day,
I promise you.
很濫情吧？
How's that
for cornball?
摀不住他們嘴巴的，先生
Nothing can
shut them up, sir.
生活委員會將再開會討論此案
The disciplinary
committee will take
this matter under advisement
in closed session.
他們在幹嘛？
What are they doin',
Charlie?
I think they're
going to come to
a decision now.
Very well.
很顯然的，不必再開會了
Apparently, that meeting
will be unnecessary.
杭賽克太太
Mrs. Hunsaker.
生活委員會不必另行開會
The joint student-faculty
disciplinary committee
needs no further sessions.
他們已達成決議
They have come to a decision.
海夫曼爾、波特
及詹姆森先生
Messrs. Havemeyer,
Potter and Jameson
因涉嫌不當作為
而留校查看
are placed on probation
for suspicion of
ungentlemanly conduct.
另外建議
喬治威利斯二世先生
It is further recommended
that Mr. George Willis, Jr.
不因其合作而做任何表揚或處分
Receive neither recognition
nor commendation
for his cooperation.
西門先生將不需
為此事件負責
Mr. Charles Simms is excused
from any further response
to this incident.
Hoo-ah!
Charlie!
小心！
有你在我很放心
Last step.
I can always count
on you, Charlie.
中校…
Colonel!
我是克莉絲汀.唐伊
政治學教授
I'm Christine Downes,
Colonel Slade.
I teach
political science.
非常感謝您的高見
I wanted to tell you
how much I appreciate
you speaking your mind.
謝謝，你結婚了？
Why, thank you.
Are you married?
I...
我在炮兵課的同學
也姓唐伊
Went to an artillery school
at Fort Sill with
a Mickey Downes.
我以為他釣上你了
Thought he might've
snagged you.
沒有呢
No, I'm afraid not.
史中校曾是詹森的幕僚
Colonel Slade was on
Lyndon Johnson's staff,
Miss Downes.
真的？太精彩了
Were you? Fascinating.
有空我們應該聊聊政治
We should get together,
talk politics sometime.
芙洛兒.狄蘿卡里絲香水
Fleurs de Rocaille.
正是！
Yes.
「小溪之花」
"Flowers from a brook."
對
That's right.
唐伊小姐
我知道到哪找你
Well, Miss Downes,
I'll know where to find you.
Charlie.
Bye, Miss Downes.
Bye.
你不必告訴我
You don't have to
tell me, Charlie.
五尺七
5'7",
赤鳶色髮
auburn hair,
美麗的棕色大眼
beautiful brown eyes.
呀吧嗒吧嘟！
Yabba-dabba-doo.
Manny.
太多了
Colonel, this
is too much.
你應得的
下次查理和我去紐約時
會再找你，你帶我們來回
Never mind,
you earned it.
Next time Charlie and I
want to take a
breather to New York,
we're gonna call you.
You can drive us
both ways.
沒問題，中校，我的榮幸
我給您打折
You're on,
Colonel.
Not only will it
be an honor,
I'll give you
a rate.
我再加倍給小費
I'll see your rate
and raise you.
保重
Stay outta
harm's way, Manny.
保重，中校
你也一樣
Take care,
Colonel.
You, too.
不，謝了，我自己走
Ready?
No. I'll take it
from here.
走吧，曼尼會送你回宿舍
You go on ahead.
Manny'll drive you
to your dorm.
聖誕節前再來
咱倆喝一杯
Come by before you
go home for Christmas.
We'll have a little cheer.
你要是願意，就留下晚餐
And if you like,
stay for dinner.
有時候她做燒雞
還能入口
Sometimes she cooks
a pot roast.
It's almost edible.
好，中校
All right, Colonel.
That'd be really...
那會是…
再見，查理
Bye, Charlie.
是誰？
是你嗎，法蘭絲？
Who's there?
That you, Francine?
Yes.
你在做什麼？
騎車
What are you doing?
Taking a ride.
讓我搭便車吧？
Taking a ride?
What about you
giving me a lift?
不要
No.
不要？
No?
拜託嘛，法蘭絲
我們重歸於好嘛
你不想跟我和我？
Come on, Francine.
We should make up.
Don't you think
it's time we made up?
不想
No.
Francine?
What?
你法蘭克叔公過了一個
很辛苦的…
感恩節週末
Uncle Frank's had
a really hard
Thanksgiving weekend.
那是什麼？
我聽到花栗鼠
還是海象？
What's that?
I hear a chipmunk.
Is it a walrus?
都不是，是威利
No, it's Willie.
要不要幫我拿提袋？
來嘛！乖
來吧
Willie, why don't you
help me with my bag?
Come on, son.
Help me with my bag.
Come on. Come on.
拿好了？拿穩哦
走
You got it. Hold onto it.
You're strong. Come on.
Here we are.
跟我和威利來
Francine, come on
with me and Willie.
你可以請我吃巧克力
好不好
I'll let you make me
some marshmallow
chocolate.
What do you say?
Good!